old två today Stop Au Briton a blessing
今日の古いテレビ 英国人を祝福するのをやめてください
TOver 100 years,11 safeguard
T100年以上、11の安全対策
idas s mattered
アイダスは重要だった
psay
サイ
call indicates
呼 indicates
Armenian ruler
アルメニアの統治者
Everyone knows that Xiaoyuan is
シャオユアンがいることは誰もが知っています
Zheyan Rescue
ゼーヤン・レスキュー
very important
とても重要な
an activity
活動
have been around for a long time
行之有年
every month
毎月
all early
都早
in various fields
さまざまな分野で
most academically accomplished
最も学術的に達成された
experts and scholars
専門家や学者
Some are from our courtyard
いくつかは私たちの中庭からのものです
some are
いくつかは
various university societies
さまざまな大学の学会
the following
以下
academia
学術界
come talk to everyone
みんなと話しに来てください
in various fields
さまざまな分野で
latest development
最新の開発
i think today we
今日は私たちだと思います
very happy
とても幸せです
also very honored
またとても光栄です
please come
来て下さい
Zheyan Rescue
ゼーヤン・レスキュー
current director of the Institute for Statistical Science
現在、統計科学研究所所長
Dr. Li Kezhao came to tell you
李克昭博士があなたに告げに来ました
The subject of our knowledge experiment this time
今回の知識実験のテーマ
Dr. Li graduated from the Mathematics Department of National Taiwan University
李博士は国立台湾大学数学科を卒業しました。
He went to the University of California, Berkeley
彼はカリフォルニア大学バークレー校に通った
Practicing a Ph.D.
博士号を取得する
practicing statistics
統計の練習
He is in residence at the University
彼は大学に滞在しています
Go to UCLA
UCLAに行く
Institute of Statistics
統計研究所
So he's basically UCLA's over there
つまり彼は基本的にUCLAにいるのです
From Professor Zhu to Distinguished Professor
朱教授から特別教授へ
Professor Li is engaged in the research of statistical theory
李教授は統計理論の研究に従事しています
His academic contributions are very high
彼の学術的貢献は非常に高い
His greatest and most admired contribution by the statistical community is in his most
統計界からの彼の最大かつ最も賞賛される貢献は、彼の最も優れた貢献です。
What is the Chinese translation? Multi-variate high-dimensional
中国語訳は何ですか? 多変量高次元
Statistical Analysis of Variables in High Dimensions
高次元の変数の統計分析
The main reason is that the actual
主な理由は、実際の
in the data used
使用したデータの中で
Whether it is experimental or natural data,
実験データであろうと自然データであろうと、
many probably almost mostly high dimensional
おそらくほとんどが高次元のものが多い
Then ordinary statistical methods to study this
次に、これを研究するための通常の統計的手法
is always flawed
いつも欠陥がある
So everyone thought of many different ways
そこでみんなで色々な方法を考えました
To use statistical methods to analyze such complex data
このような複雑なデータを統計的手法を使用して分析するには
Neither was very successful
どちらもあまり成功しませんでした
Dr. Li invented a method in the 1990s
リー博士は1990年代にある方法を発明した
It is recognized by everyone as doing this thing
こういうことをやっていると誰もが認める
One of the most effective and best ways
最も効果的で最良の方法の 1 つ
So his contribution in this aspect is really quite big.
したがって、この点における彼の貢献は本当に非常に大きいです。
In the last ten years or so, he has put his interest in biostatistics,
ここ 10 年ほど、彼は生物統計学に興味を持っています。
The achievements above are also very large.
上記の成果も非常に大きいです。
Since he returned to Taiwan six years ago and served as the director of the ten-year research institute,
6年前に台湾に戻り、10年間研究所所長を務めて以来、
With Taiwanese scholars, especially Taiwanese medical scholars,
台湾の学者、特に台湾の医学者たちと、
Cooperate with doctors who actually work and use the latest statistical methods,
実際に勤務する医師と連携し、最新の統計手法を活用し、
Do very difficult, but also very important analysis of biological and medical data.
非常に困難ですが、非常に重要な生物学的データと医療データの分析を実行します。
He and the very outstanding scholars of National Taiwan University,
彼と国立台湾大学の非常に優れた学者たち、
Including Yang Pangci, the dean of the School of Medicine at National Taiwan University
国立台湾大学医学部長の楊方慈氏を含む
Academician lung cancer group
学会員肺がんグループ
made recent quite groundbreaking research results
最近非常に画期的な研究結果を発表しました
These results have been used in practical medicine
これらの結果は実際の医療に活用されています
Medical top
メディカルトップ
Today he talked about this topic
今日彼はこの話題について話しました
apply other statistical methods
他の統計手法を適用する
Statistical processing and analysis of genetic technology information
遺伝子技術情報の統計処理・解析
He called him chaos
彼は彼をカオスと呼んだ
let's welcome him
彼を歓迎しましょう
I choose this topic today
今日はこのテーマを選びます
The first aspect is my interest
最初の側面は私の興味です
On the other hand, because I know the words of this talk
一方、私はこの話の言葉を知っているので、
There are many different backgrounds for this listener
このリスナーにはさまざまな背景があります
When it comes to statistics, most people are in awe of three points
統計に関して言えば、ほとんどの人は次の 3 つの点に関心を持ちます。
My cesar advisor is called prof. Jack Heaver
私のセザール顧問はジャック・ヒーバー教授と呼ばれています
He is also a National Academician of the United States unfortunately a year early four
彼は残念ながら4年早く米国の国立学者でもあります。
He once said that when he was flying
彼はかつて飛行機に乗っているときにこう言った
There's a lady sitting next to me
私の隣に女性が座っています
Then the two of you chatted and it was very interesting
それからお二人のおしゃべりはとても面白かったです
what do you do
職業はなんですか
He said I was a professor of statistics
彼は私が統計学の教授だと言いました
Immediately stand alone
すぐに一人で立つ
i hate statistics
私は統計が嫌いです
Because statistics have a whole bunch of companies
統計にはたくさんの企業が含まれているため
How is it? I don't know what's going on inside
どうですか？中で何が起こっているのか分かりません
The words in my talk today
今日の私の話の中の言葉
I want to change your point of view
あなたの視点を変えたい
Because statistics are actually because there are many such computers and so on.
なぜなら、統計というのは、実際にはそのようなコンピューターなどがたくさんあるからです。
Can help you deal with those company issues
企業の問題に対処するのに役立ちます
Your company doesn't need to memorize it, you only need to memorize it once
会社はそれを暗記する必要はありません。一度暗記するだけで十分です。
The rest of the things are called pressing a button and everything comes out.
残りはボタンを押すと呼ばれるもので、すべてが出てきます。
So what the memory worker is is not a very important key
したがって、メモリワーカーが何であるかはそれほど重要な鍵ではありません
The most important key is statistical thinking
最も重要な鍵は統計的思考です
This is a fairly logical thinking
これはかなり論理的な考え方です
Then this processing data
そして、この処理データ
You see or see some information in the society, etc.
社会などで何らかの情報を見たり見たりします。
I hope that it can have this statistical spirit in it
この統計的精神がそこに含まれていることを願っています
Then see a lot of that
それからそれをたくさん見てください
It's a social thing and you'll keep it in your heart
それは社会的なものであり、心の中に留めておきます
The most basic characteristic of that statistician
その統計学者の最も基本的な特徴
He just won't believe him when he sees the information
彼はその情報を見ても信じないだろう
He will answer a big question mark
彼は大きな疑問符に答えるだろう
so
それで
Is it really like that?
本当にそうなのでしょうか？
Then I think today although I use the
そこで今日思うのは、 を使っているのですが、
This biotechnology information
このバイオテクノロジー情報は、
Then I hope that the last message brought to you is a concept
それでは、あなたに伝えた最後のメッセージがコンセプトであることを願っています
Everyone can use it in daily life
誰もが日常生活で使用できます
Thanks
ありがとう
Well, that gene we all know now
さて、私たち全員が今知っているその遺伝子
science is very advanced
科学は非常に進んでいます
The species that says mostly a lot cannot say most
ほとんど多くのことを語る種は、ほとんどのことを語ることはできない
The sequencing of the genes of many species has come to an end
多くの種の遺伝子の配列決定が終了した
And what about the next job?
そして次の仕事はどうなるのでしょうか？
biologists rely on some so-called vitamin
生物学者はいわゆるビタミンに依存しています
this way or vitamin glyconucleic acid
この方法または複合糖質
And some Next Generation
そしていくつかの次世代
This is something that the second generation is sequenced to and so on
これは第 2 世代でシーケンスされるものなどです。
generate a lot of data
大量のデータを生成する
Use it to help with complex diseases such as cancer
がんなどの複雑な病気の治療に役立てる
research or you are in crops you want to change its important shape
研究している場合、または重要な形状を変更したい作物に携わっている場合
For example, genetic factors such as endurance, high yield, etc.
たとえば、持久力や収量の多さなどの遺伝的要因です。
So in so many different fields
非常に多くのさまざまな分野で
Different in the domain of this creature
この生き物の領域では異なります
Everyone uses especially the same nature of these materials
誰もがこれらの材料の特に同じ性質を使用します
Then how to rely on this computer to wait for this
では、このコンピューターに依存してこれを待つにはどうすればよいでしょうか。
grant to do this analysis of the data
このデータ分析を行うための助成金
find out the rules
ルールを見つけてください
Well that's an interesting question for the guy we do the stats
そうですね、統計を担当している人にとっては興味深い質問ですね
Because there are so many variables involved
非常に多くの変数が関係しているため、
So today I mainly give some simple examples to introduce to you.
そこで今日は簡単な例を中心に紹介します。
And when it comes to statistics, like the average person pays this head on
そして統計に関して言えば、平均的な人がこれを正面から支払うのと同じように、
It's like this striking power, like Wang Jianmin's
この打撃力は王建民のようなものです
It depends on how much impact you need.
それは必要な衝撃力によって異なります。
or some polls
またはいくつかの世論調査
Like how many people win a certain policy
特定の政策を何人が獲得するかなど
while opposed to etc.
などに反対しながら。
then why did i choose to do this
それで、なぜ私はこれをすることにしたのですか
biology
biology 生物
This time the most important thing is
今回一番大事なことは、
because according to many people
なぜなら多くの人によると
The so-called 21st century is
いわゆる21世紀は、
Nero, Bio, Info
ネロ、バイオ、情報
that is to say
つまり
Nero is Namimi's technology
ネロはナミミの技術です
Then Bio is biology
じゃあバイオは生物学だ
Info is information
情報は情報だ
The so-called three major technologies of the 21st century
いわゆる21世紀の三大技術
Of course statistics are not here
もちろん統計はここにはありません
very frivolous
非常沾閃邊
Then I chose this piece because of this
それでこの作品を選んだのはこんな理由からです
biology he is gradually changing
彼は徐々に変化している生物学
that he
彼が
by some of the past
過去のいくつかによって
Probably some observations and some more qualitative
おそらくいくつかの観察とより定性的なもの
east and west
的東西
Record what this thing is when you see it
これを見たときにそれが何であるかを記録してください
Work like that gradually
徐々にそのように取り組んでください
Doing some rather quantitative reason is quite quantitative
かなり定量的な理由を行うことは非常に定量的です
need to make some inferences
いくつかの推論をする必要がある
this kind of work
この種の仕事
That's what makes this a lot of mathematicians including statistics
それが統計を含む数学者が多い理由です。
Mathematicians, including scientists, have a lot of room for this activity
科学者を含む数学者には、この活動の余地がたくさんあります
Then we can use some of our thinking abilities
そうすれば、私たちの思考能力の一部を活用できるようになります
come to help
助けに来てください
this from this
これから
huge amount of this
これの膨大な量
Find some rules in financial data
財務データからいくつかのルールを見つける
The human genome is
ヒトゲノムは、
This financial project
この金融プロジェクトは、
It was roughly completed around the beginning of 2000 AD
西暦2000年初頭頃に大まかに完成
The main thing is to do some regular work
重要なのは定期的な仕事をすることです
that in that respect
その点では
At the beginning, everyone thought there were about 30,000 gold
最初は誰もがゴールドが 30,000 ほどあると思っていました
But now it turns out that there aren't that many
しかし、今ではそれほど多くはないことが判明しました
More than 30,000 gold is mainly based on some knowledge at that time
30,000ゴールド以上は主に当時の知識に基づいています
Estimated from some computers
一部のコンピュータから推定
Then this slide was produced by the US Department of Energy
このスライドは米国エネルギー省によって作成されました。
Originally promoted this project
もともとこのプロジェクトを推進していた
Then the remaining problems after decoding begin
その後、デコード後の残りの問題が始まります
Because there are twenty-five thousand gold
ゴールドが二万五千あるから
What is the function of each gold?
それぞれの金にはどんな役割があるのでしょうか？
Then is it in the genome world
じゃあゲノムの世界か
Different genes can form a functional body
異なる遺伝子が機能的な体を形成することができる
between the different functions
異なる機能の間で
What is its interactive relationship like?
そのインタラクティブな関係はどのようなものですか?
Then there are two-year-old cells
次に2年目の細胞があります
How do you use these genes to regulate his metabolism?
これらの遺伝子をどのように使って彼の代謝を調節するのでしょうか?
issues of growth
成長の問題
Then there are many problems
それから、問題がたくさんあります
a bunch of these
これらの束
Iton, I can’t talk to each and every one of you
イトン、皆さん一人一人と話すことはできません
introduce
導入
That
それか
So from
だから、から
In basic biology, there is probably an idea that it is hoped that the
基礎生物学ではおそらく、
use these genes
これらの遺伝子を利用する
This information about genes
遺伝子に関するこの情報
Then form a science
そして科学を形成する
then research this
それからこれを調べてください
The various components in this cell
このセル内のさまざまなコンポーネント
Then
それから
To describe which gene has how much?
どの遺伝子がどのくらいの量を持っているかを説明するには?
then when does he show it
それで彼はいつそれを見せるのですか
What is the result of his performance and his influence?
彼のパフォーマンスと彼の影響力はどのような結果をもたらしたのでしょうか?
Wait, make a big, big mathematical model
待って、大きな大きな数学モデルを作ってください
Then right on the computer you might be able to
そうすれば、コンピュータ上で次のことができるかもしれません
Even make a so-called Virtual Cell
いわゆるバーチャルセルも作る
just one by one
ひとつひとつだけ
imaginary this
想像上のこれ
cell but
セルだけど
The function inside is just like the performance inside
内部の機能は内部のパフォーマンスと同じです
It is exactly the same as normal real cells
通常の実際の細胞とまったく同じです
So it's a fairly
それで、それはかなりです
It's a pretty great one
かなり素晴らしいものです
enough for me to be there
私がそこにいるだけで十分です
Hope to be able to do some cells
いくつかのセルを実行できることを願っています
How do you respond to external stimuli?
外部からの刺激に対してどのように反応しますか？
But before accomplishing such a great task
しかし、そのような偉大な任務を達成する前に、
This Medical Research
この医学研究
In fact, it is more advanced
実際はもっと進化してるよ
they can't wait
彼らは待ちきれない
Because if you want to do this basic scientific research
なぜなら、もしこの基礎的な科学研究をしたいのであれば、
Nothing to do with practicality
実用性とは関係ない
In fact, there is no support from any government
実際のところ、政府からの支援はありません
Because it is a complex disease with many direct
直接的な要因がたくさんある複雑な病気なので、
Everyone thinks it has something to do with genes
遺伝子が関係していると誰もが思っている
what is the relationship
関係は何ですか
how to use these
これらの使い方
Although the knowledge of this gene body of the incisor just now
この切歯の遺伝子本体の知識は今さらですが
is able to do some help
何らかの手助けができる
just inside
すぐ内側
I will list one here
ここに一つ挙げておきます
Currently doing the easiest to identify
現在、最も簡単に識別できるようにしています
a doable goal
実行可能な目標
so-called molecular diagnosis
いわゆる分子診断
is the traditional words
伝統的な言葉です
according to the pathologist
病理学者によると
this slice and so on
このスライスなど
make some judgments
何らかの判断を下す
Judgments like that are often wrong
そういった判断は間違っていることが多い
Method doesn't get enough queries
メソッドが十分なクエリを取得できない
So now based on some molecular
それで今、いくつかの分子に基づいて
The method is through some genetic
その方法は遺伝によるものです
performance measurement
パフォーマンス測定
See if there are any mutations in the gene, etc.
遺伝子などに変異がないか調べます。
do some diagnostics
いくつかの診断を行う
Then
それから
So his goal is to hope that this
したがって、彼の目標は、これが実現することを期待することです
Physicians can use this
医師はこれを使用できます
Before diseased tissue stroke
病変組織の脳卒中前
can predict
予測できる
express like cancer cells are
がん細胞のように発現します
it might happen etc.
起こるかもしれないなど
and then further able to
そしてさらにできるようになります
The medical quality of treatment has
治療の医療の質は、
substantial improvement
大幅な改善
and then even
そしてさらに
Someone mentioned whether your genes are bad
誰かがあなたの遺伝子が悪いかどうかについて言及しました
I can help you remodel and so on.
リフォームなどお手伝いさせていただきます。
Then when we talked about how to do this analysis
次に、この分析をどのように行うかについて話したとき、
Such complex information on this gene was previously
この遺伝子に関するこのような複雑な情報は、以前は
We must have some of the most basic of this
この最も基本的なものをいくつか理解する必要があります
Ballage Background
バラージュの背景
So I'll post it in a few minutes
それでは数分以内に投稿します
Soon Goal through these so-called Knowledge
これらのいわゆる知識を通じてすぐに目標を達成する
So if this is the case
したがって、これが事実であれば
We have some consensus in the talk below
以下の会話では一定の合意があります
Then one of the most basic biological
次に、最も基本的な生物学的要素の 1 つは、
a so-called law
いわゆる法律
A dogma is its message
教義とはそのメッセージである
It's inside the organism called the cell
それは細胞と呼ばれる生物の内部にあります
Its communication The communication of this instruction is from
その通信 この指示の通信は、
this DNA
このDNA
Then inside this chromosome
そして、この染色体の中に
Then this DNA
そうするとこのDNAは
Chrysostom
クリュソストム
Then after this transcription is transferred to
この転写が転送された後、
into this messenger RNA
このメッセンジャーRNAに
messenger RNA
メッセンジャーRNA
Then translate into this protein after translation
翻訳後にこのタンパク質に翻訳されます
is our protein
私たちのタンパク質です
Some biological functions are carried out by proteins
一部の生物学的機能はタンパク質によって実行されます
That is of course a dogma here
もちろんそれはここでの定説です
For everything in biology, there are examples and there must be counterexamples.
生物学のあらゆるものには例があり、反例も必ず存在します。
So there are counterexamples
つまり反例があります
So there are quite a few cases like this one
なので、このようなケースは結構あります
information flow will be
情報の流れは
not complied with
不被遵守的
that that
それは
you open a cell
あなたはセルを開きます
Fetch something from the cell when it makes sense
意味がある場合はセルから何かを取得します
The most important component is the chromosome
最も重要な要素は染色体です
Chromosome words
染色体の単語
We all know it is through
私たちは皆、それが終わったことを知っています
Four different nucleotide compositions
4 つの異なるヌクレオチド組成
ATG type
ATG型
that's a pair
それはペアです
Then it's highly congruent
そうすると非常に一致します
These two will
この二人は
If it is A, it must be received by T.
A を取得した場合は、T を取得する必要があります。
If it is G, it must be received by C.
G の場合は、C が受信する必要があります。
Then you don't understand people's words
そうなると人の言葉が理解できなくなる
conceivably say yes
おそらく「はい」と言うでしょう
A is a relatively large
Aは比較的大きいです
This probably is
これはおそらく、
Then T is relatively small
すると T は比較的小さい
so one big and one small
大きいものと小さいもの
This way it matches Size
こうすることでサイズが一致します
That G is relatively large
Gが比較的大きいこと
That C is relatively small
C が比較的小さいこと
no symmetrical relationship
対称的な関係はない
Then A cannot match G
その場合、A は G と一致しません
etc.
等
That gene is actually this
その遺伝子は実はこれなんです
the whole this very long this
全体的にこれはとても長いです
A short passage from ChromoSong
ChromoSong からの短い一節
a fragment of it
その断片
it has a message
それはメッセージを持っています
kana order
かなorder
what is its message
そのメッセージは何ですか
based on these
これらに基づいて
Let's say your DNA is double-stranded
あなたの DNA が二本鎖だとしましょう
then you are single
それならあなたは独身です
For example, this stock is GCA
たとえば、この株はGCAです。
GCA will be transferred
GCAは移転されます
translates to an amino acid
アミノ酸に翻訳される
We have a total of 20 different amino acids
アミノ酸は全部で20種類あります
20 amino acids are arranged and combined through ATGC
ATGCにより20個のアミノ酸を配列・結合
translate it
翻訳してください
After talking about genes
遺伝子の話をした後
an important thing
重要なこと
It's this Messenger
このメッセンジャーです
ribonucleic acid
リボ核酸
What is message RNA
メッセージRNAとは
It is a certain segment in this DNA
それはこの DNA の特定の部分です
Especially in this part of the gene
特に遺伝子のこの部分では
near the gene
遺伝子の近くにある
it will have a
それは
This mechanism puts the ATGC of this section
このメカニズムは、このセクションの ATGC を配置します。
make a copy of it
それのコピーを作成します
copy over
コピーオーバー
Then this copy will be sent outside the cell box
その後、このコピーはセルボックスの外に送信されます
Then go through this Ribosol
次に、このリボソルを通過します
Ribosol imagined as a large
リボソルは大きなものとして想像されます
processing plant a manufacturing machine
加工工場、製造機械
It can put this oil slick in the cytoplasm
この油膜を細胞質に入れることができます
Some amino acids hold it together piece by piece like this
いくつかのアミノ酸がこのように少しずつ結合させています
According to your ATGC
ATGC によると
It will look for those relative Amino Acid
それらの相対的なアミノ酸を探します
snap it out like this
このようにパチンと外します
So there's nothing wrong with that
それで何も問題ないよ
So this is a natural structure like this
これは自然な構造です
That is, a certain section of your ATGC will be automatically translated
つまり、ATGC の特定のセクションが自動的に翻訳されます。
I just said that's right
まさにその通りだと言いました
In fact all living organisms
実はすべての生き物は
In fact, there are quite a lot of mistakes
実は間違いがかなり多いのです
is a lot
たくさんあります
Then it will have some correction mechanism
そうすれば、何らかの修正メカニズムが備わります
The words there are also a great knowledge
そこにある言葉も素晴らしい知識です
This is a different version of what I just said.
これは私が今言ったことの別のバージョンです。
This view wing map is the nucleus.
このビューウィングマップが核となります。
Then through this transfer work from the gene
そして、この遺伝子からの伝達作業を通じて
Why do cells need to do the job of transferring
なぜ細胞は転送という仕事をする必要があるのですか
At first I thought it was strong
最初は強いと思った
Because you are inside the Cromosome of the Code of DNA
なぜなら、あなたはDNAの暗号の染色体の中にいるからです。
If you use this Ribos every time
毎回このリボスを使うなら
What you want to transfer is directly from this gene
あなたが移したいものはこの遺伝子から直接のものです
If the code comes out directly
コードが直接出てくる場合
The original one is often used
オリジナルのものがよく使われます
So he can be easily damaged
だから彼は簡単に傷つくことができる
It doesn't matter if you destroy this Messenger IM
このメッセンジャーIMは破壊しても問題ありません
because you regenerated
あなたが再生したから
You can also copy one more
もう 1 つコピーすることもできます
So this is a pretty clever design
これはかなり賢いデザインです
At the same time, in higher organisms
同時に高等生物では
it has a nucleus
核があるんだよ
Then the outer words are the cytoplasm
そして、外側の言葉は細胞質です
So these Messenger IMs will be sent out
したがって、これらのメッセンジャー IM は送信されます
so inside it won't
だから内部ではそうならない
There will be a state of traffic chaos
交通混乱の状態
So we just talked about this protein
それで、私たちはちょうどこのタンパク質について話しました
Protein is made up of 20 Armino-S
タンパク質は20個のArmino-Sで構成されています
A series of Armino-S for sightseeing
観光用アルミノSシリーズ
Actually it doesn't work by itself
実際にはそれ自体では機能しません
it relies on some of its
それはその一部に依存しています
interaction near each other
近くでの相互作用
Form a so-called Protin Fold
いわゆるタンパク質の折り畳みを形成する
it has to be folded into a shape
ある形に折りたたむ必要があります
this shape it is
この形です
The most important protin is relying on its shape
最も重要なタンパク質はその形状に依存します
Is there a hole in it or something?
穴か何かあるのでしょうか？
To determine its nature
その性質を判断するには
words like this are
このような言葉は
This is to show
これは示すためのものです
A synthetic beauty called ATD inside the force line body
フォースラインボディ内部のATDと呼ばれる合成美
ATD is what we call Hot Cache of Energy
ATD はエネルギーのホット キャッシュと呼ばれるものです
thermal diving
サーマルダイビング
if you want to generate fuel
燃料を生成したい場合
You must go through ATD
ATDを通過する必要があります
This one in the vertical line is a synthesis of ATV
こちらの縦列はATVの合成です
In this two different this
この 2 つの違いでは、
There is an EcoLine in the bio, which is what the large intestine looks like inside
バイオには大腸の内部の様子を示す EcoLine があります。
the words on the left
左側の言葉
I didn't write this here like a monkey or an orangutan
私はサルやオランウータンのようにここにこれを書いたわけではありません
They look the same, but they are actually very similar, although the level of this creature is much different.
同じように見えますが、この生き物のレベルは大きく異なりますが、実際は非常に似ています。
But it's fairly consistent on the most basic units
しかし、最も基本的な単位に関してはかなり一貫しています。
At the same time, it can be seen that the ProtinBis attachment I just mentioned
同時に、先ほど述べた ProtinBis アタッチメントが
very church made form
まさに教会が作った形
attached to a different this shape
別のこの形状に取り付けられています
It's like a jigsaw puzzle, especially so this
ジグソーパズルのようなものです、特にこれは
this is a very interesting question
これはとても興味深い質問です
OK
OK
The other more interesting question is that we have the same memory
もう一つのもっと興味深い質問は、私たちは同じ記憶を持っているということです
We know that after the combination of the heavy bag and the gold side of the egg
重い袋と卵の金色の面を組み合わせると、
This one cell begins to divide
この一つの細胞が分裂を始める
Those cells will grow into different tissues
それらの細胞は異なる組織に成長します
The DNA in every tissue is actually the same
すべての組織の DNA は実際には同じです
then you will wonder why
そうしたら、なぜだろうと思うでしょう
The shape of the nose is different from the glasses
メガネと鼻の形が違う
The cells in there are exactly the same
そこにある細胞はまったく同じです
That is how the matter
それが問題のやり方です
The mechanism is in the expression of this gene
そのメカニズムはこの遺伝子の発現にあります
Because you will form a different organization
違う組織を作るから
And the results of many different protins will be different
そして、多くの異なるタンパク質の結果は異なります
Those protins are expressed by the wear debris gene
これらのタンパク質は摩耗粉遺伝子によって発現されます。
that's in a different organization
それは別の組織にいます
The expression of various genes will be relatively different
さまざまな遺伝子の発現は相対的に異なります
so in this
それでこれで
Slowly distribute from this embryo
この胚からゆっくりと分配します
it's a lot of fun
とても楽しいです
Which genes are expressed and when
どの遺伝子がいつ発現するか
Anyway, those things are formed first
とにかく、それらが最初に形成されます
what is formed after
その後に何が形成されるか
That's a whole lot of knowledge
それはとてもたくさんの知識です
Biologists rely on data
生物学者はデータに頼る
Such a large data transfer
このような大規模なデータ転送
Slowly and slowly make this thing out again
ゆっくりゆっくり、これをもう一度出してください
I just talked about how cells receive external stimuli
細胞が外部刺激をどのように受け取るかについてお話しました。
and then some reactions will come out
そして、何らかの反応が出てくるでしょう
let it grow etc.
成長させてくださいなど。
this is a wanton
これはとんでもないことだ
It is to receive some stimuli from the outside in the biological cells
生体細胞が外部から何らかの刺激を受けることです。
usually on the outermost part of the cell
通常、細胞の最も外側の部分にあります
There are some proteins called receptor protein
レセプタータンパク質と呼ばれるタンパク質があります
lean body
体を傾けろ
will accept small molecules
小さな分子を受け入れます
put this together
これを一緒にします
Then it will have some chemical management
その後、化学物質管理が必要になります
wait
待って
and then at the end its ultimate goal
そして最後にその究極の目標が
is it possible to send this message to
このメッセージをに送信することはできますか
inside the nucleus
核の内部
Then there will be some of this protein
次に、このタンパク質の一部が存在します
These proteins are called transcription factors
これらのタンパク質は転写因子と呼ばれます
The protein will bind to the DNA
タンパク質はDNAに結合します
Then bring a certain segment of the gene
次に、遺伝子の特定の部分を取り出します
This section of the gene it will
遺伝子のこのセクションは、
copied by this into this
this によって this にコピーされました
message says this
メッセージにはこう書かれています
Then through the message, there will be protein
そしてメッセージを通して、プロテインが生まれる
then there will be some
そうすればいくつかあるでしょう
The role of protein
protein 的作用
those effects
それらの効果
It can also drive and possibly interact with other protein
また、他のタンパク質を駆動し、場合によっては相互作用することもできます。
driving combination etc.
ドライビングコンビネーションなど
So accept this signal from the outside
だから、この外部からの信号を受け入れてください
There are a lot of proteins, there are a lot of receptors
タンパク質がたくさんあり、受容体もたくさんあります
So you can accept different signal
したがって、異なる信号を受け入れることができます
so which protein
それでどのプロテイン
Can
できる
What kind of signal does this accept
これはどのような信号を受け付けますか
Then what happens underneath
ではその下では何が起こっているのか
This whole thing is called signal transduction
この全体をシグナル伝達と呼びます
chain of information transfer
情報伝達の連鎖
This is something that biologists really want to know
これは生物学者が本当に知りたいことです
That also relies on the so-called bi-information
それもいわゆる二情報に依存します
is what bioinformaticians are currently doing
それは生物情報学者が現在行っていることです
Let’s go back to what we just said that the entire length of Keelung has about three B-faces.
基隆全体には長さ約 3 つの B 面があるという先ほどの話に戻りましょう。
30 3 billion Nuclear type base failure
30 30億的Nuclear type base failure
So there is a lot of information in the words
言葉の中にはたくさんの情報が含まれているので、
Now we know that there are about 25,000 genes
現在、遺伝子は約 25,000 個あることがわかっています。
Then it occupies only a small part of Keelung
基隆のほんの一部を占めるだけです
But there is a so-called intro in this gene
しかし、この遺伝子にはいわゆるイントロがあります
There is so-called excel
いわゆるエクセルというものがあります
intron is the useful part
イントロンは便利な部分です
intron is the useless part
イントロンは無駄な部分です
extron is the useful part
extron は便利な部分です
Then there are some permutations and combinations of these
次に、これらの順列と組み合わせがいくつかあります
Then what is the outside of this gincoding doing?
では、この gincoding の外側は何をしているのでしょうか?
I used to think it was junk
ジャンクだと思ってた
But now it is very important
でも今はとても大事なことです
Because there are some transcription factors
転写因子があるから
to bind in front
前で縛る
Then if it says that it was stimulated by some fakes, etc.
そうすると、何かのフェイクなどに刺激されたと言われれば。
then it won't work
それではうまくいきません
So there is a lot of research on that area.
したがって、その分野については多くの研究が行われています。
So this transfer medicine
それでこの転送薬は
It is hoped that through these genes
これらの遺伝子を通じて、
able to promote these
これらを促進できる
Immediately be able to do something that can be done immediately
すぐにできることはすぐにできる
the most important job
最も重要な仕事
Of course, is it the information
もちろん情報ですよ
can be used to help patients survive
患者の生存を助けるために使用できる
survival of life
生命の生存
Of course there is some information
もちろん情報もありますよ
used to help patients survive
患者の生存を助けるために使用される
survival of life
生命の生存
of course live
もちろんライブ
So the first question is to say
最初の質問はこう言います
Are you able to rely on the information
その情報は信頼できますか
can be used to predict
予測に使用できます
don't talk yet
まだ話さないでください
First predict to see how long he can survive the patient
まず、患者がどれくらい生存できるかを予測します
According to your comprehension
あなたの理解によると
no choice
選択の余地ない
From these materials
これらの資料から
can be compared to the traditional for example
たとえば、従来のものと比較できます
Staging
演出
you heard this
あなたはこれを聞きました
stage of lung cancer
肺がんの段階
What is the approximate survival rate?
おおよその生存率はどれくらいですか?
Is it better than those
それらよりも優れていますか
there is this pathologist
この病理学者がいます
according to their tissue lesions
組織病変に応じて
See if he transfers and so on
彼が異動するかどうかを確認するなど
able to be more precise
より正確にできる
this is the first goal
これが最初の目標です
And what about the second goal?
では、2点目についてはどうでしょうか？
can you can
できますか
according to your this
あなたによるとこれ
Elite performance status
エリートのパフォーマンスステータス
see if i use this drug
この薬を使用するかどうか確認してください
how will he react
彼はどう反応するだろうか
He can
彼はできる
more effective
さらに効果的な
or less effective
または効果が低い
even
平
I hope to do some two-case detection
2つのケースの検出を実行したいと考えています
before the disease occurs
病気が起こる前に
let's see if
どうか見てみましょう
start soon
すぐに始めます
Then try to do prevention
それから予防に努めてください
finally
ついに
Of course, you can hope to improve your quality of life
もちろん生活の質の向上も期待できます
quality of your life
あなたの生活の質
Then we use the so-called this
次に、いわゆるこれを使用します
What exactly is this resource?
このリソースは正確には何ですか?
what can be used is
使えるものは
this
これ
Biochemists have many techniques
生化学者は多くの技術を持っています
Now this biotechnology can see a lot of data
今、このバイオテクノロジーは多くのデータを見ることができます
probably which data
おそらくどのデータ
my side
私の側
just slightly
ほんの少しだけ
describe
説明
there is
がある
micro array is
マイクロアレイは
micro certificate list
マイクロ証明書リスト
genetic information
遺伝情報
Then there is another
それから、もう一つあります
called
呼ばれた
array CGS
配列CGS
array CGS is fetched
配列 CGS が取得されます
Probe says it's this
プローブはこれだと言う
DNA的 copy
DNAのコピー
it is known
周知された
that usually
それは通常
A Sale has two chromosons, that is, a pair
セールには 2 つの染色体、つまりペアがあります。
If you card DNA, you have Kirby
DNAをカード化すればカービィが手に入ります
but in some cases
しかし場合によっては
no change etc.
変化なしなど
It will be more than Number for this card
このカードの数値以上になります
For a certain paragraph it is
ある段落に関しては、
The reason for how to continue has been repeated many times
続ける理由は何度も繰り返した
repeat a lot
たくさん繰り返す
Then you will affect the expression of the last gene
そうすれば、最後の遺伝子の発現に影響を与えることになります
It's just that certain genes are overexpressed
特定の遺伝子が過剰発現しているだけです
Sometimes those Kabi Numbers suddenly decrease a bit
カビの数値が突然少し減少することがあります
That's the part that doesn't work
それは機能しない部分です
or for no reason
あるいは理由もなく
when passing from one generation to the next
ある世代から次の世代に受け継がれるとき
lost
失った
Then there is Single Nucretypulomorphism
次に、単一核型同型性があります。
This is a genetic variant
これは遺伝的変異です
This piece is also quite a lot of information
この作品もかなりの情報量です
Then there is something called Transcription Factor
それから転写因子と呼ばれるものがあります
Information about Binding Side
Binding Side的資料
is what we just mentioned
それは私たちが今述べたことです
A Transcription Factor
一個Transcription Factor
Can Binding in this
缶バインディングはこれで
Where is this DNA
このDNAはどこにあるのか
什麼transcription factor by the way
ちなみに転写因子は何ですか
this is a great knowledge
これは素晴らしい知識です
There are some techniques that can be used
使えるテクニックもいくつかある
There is also one called micro-init
micro-initと呼ばれるものもあります
This is a violation of the peace talks
これは和平交渉違反だ
those performance
それらのパフォーマンス
Very important
非常重要
That
それか
this is currently
これは現在です
The so-called very, very popular one that everyone talks about is very expensive.
いわゆるみんなが話題にする大人気のものは非常に高価です。
that is
あれは
This sequence in the new century
新世紀のこのシーケンス
He took this test
彼はこのテストを受けました
a whole genome of this
このゲノム全体
DNA
DNA
each nuclear
それぞれの核
can order it out
注文できます
In the past, this was an impossible, almost impossible task.
以前は、これは不可能、ほとんど不可能に近い作業でした。
Too much
過度に
but now
でも今
you actually
あなたは実際に
can be in about a week or two
約1週間か2週間以内になる可能性があります
you can put your gene
自分の遺伝子を入れることができる
genetic
遺伝的
All the nuclear all take you
すべての核はすべてあなたを連れて行きます
order out
注文する
This progress is very open
この進歩は非常にオープンです
but still quite expensive
しかし、それでもかなり高価です
Then my most important thing today is
それでは、今日私が最も重要なことは、
focus on this
これに焦点を当ててください
micro rate of this technique
このテクニックのマイクロレート
that many other this
他にもこれがたくさん
Race, CHF, SNP
人種、スイスフラン、SNP
His basic spirit is the same as this
彼の基本的な精神はこれと同じです
that next generation
その次世代
He made it completely different
彼はそれを全く違うものにしてくれた
technique
技術
But we use some statistical methods
ただし、いくつかの統計的手法を使用します
can pass
通過できる
use that
それを使って
micro
マイクロ
This is a micro certificate column
これはマイクロ証明書の列です
This chip is certified
このチップは認定されています
it looks like this
このように見えます
every place words
あらゆる場所の言葉
there is a spot of light
光点がある
The brightness of this spot
この場所の明るさ
represent this place
この場所を代表する
it's early
早いです
this
これ
This Messenger ion is bright
このメッセンジャーイオンは明るいです
every imaginable
考えられるすべての
Every place is a carbon needle
あらゆる場所がカーボン針です
ours
私たちのもの
can put
置くことができます
All genes are one by one
すべての遺伝子は一つ一つ
straight up here
ここにまっすぐに
because we already know its sequence
なぜなら私たちはすでにその順序を知っているからです
Then
それから
that according to its this
それによるとこれ
on the DNA
DNAについて
complementary binding
相補的結合
is A to G
AからGまでです
G to C
GからCまで
so
それで
it can find its relative
相対的なものを見つけることができます
stick it on
貼ってください
So the whole technology is already very mature.
つまり、テクノロジー全体はすでに非常に成熟しています。
so
それで
This microRNA can
このマイクロRNAは、
because it's pretty much telling you how much the gene is expressed
なぜなら、それは遺伝子がどれだけ発現されているかをほぼ教えてくれるからです
How much is this gene expressed
この遺伝子はどのくらい発現しているのか
so it can be used for many things
なので色々なことに使えます
mark this creature
この生き物にマークを付ける
do this
これを行う
with this
これとともに
With this biomarker some drugs can be developed
このバイオマーカーを使用すると、いくつかの薬を開発できます
We can use the expression of these genes to divide cancer
これらの遺伝子の発現を利用してがんを分割することができます
So it's very, very useful
とてもとても便利です
Then this is just one of the earliest applications
これは初期のアプリケーションの 1 つにすぎません
The Elegant group of the Broad Institute in the United States made such a result very early
米国のブロード研究所のエレガントなグループは、非常に早い段階でこのような結果を出しました。
There are two different types of Leukemia related to leukemia
白血病に関連する白血病には2つの異なるタイプがあります
in terms of gene expression
遺伝子発現の観点から
We find the set of genes
遺伝子セットを見つける
Leukemia performance is relatively high
Leukemia表現比較高
In AML, it is the snow white disease of acute femoral water disease
AMLでは、急性大腿骨水疾患の白雪姫のような病気です。
low performance
表現比較低
Another set of genes is just the opposite
別の遺伝子セットはまったく逆です
Since you can find genes like this
このような遺伝子が見つかるので、
So in the future you have to use it to judge that it is the ideal of this person.
だから今後はそれを使って「この人の理想だ」と判断しなければなりません。
What type of this Rukimia got
ルキミアは何の種類を持っていますか
by measuring the expression of these genes
これらの遺伝子の発現を測定することによって
make a judgment
判断を下す
Then let me briefly introduce
それでは簡単にご紹介させていただきます
This is mine just now
これは今の私のものです
Director Liu Fuye also mentioned this National Taiwan University
劉福禎院長もこの国立台湾大学について言及
That Professor Yang Panzi is currently the dean of this medical school
楊潘子教授は現在この医科大学の学部長である
What their research team is doing
彼らの研究チームは何をしているのか
that their most important
彼らの最も重要なこと
is doing lung cancer research
肺がんの研究を行っています
What about lung cancer?
肺がんについてはどうですか？
in taiwan can
台湾ではできる
There are two types of lung cancer
肺がんには2種類ある
is a small cell
小さな細胞です
one is non-small cell
1 つは非スモールセルです
Anyway, of course there are other kinds
もちろん他にも種類はありますが、
The current research
現在の研究
So the hot part is no longer small cells
つまり、ホットな部分は小さなセルではなくなります
Because non-small cells are more
非小細胞の方が多いため、
nephrocytes
腎細胞
Non-small cells can be further divided into two categories
非スモールセルはさらに 2 つのカテゴリに分類できます
One is an Arduino Castle
1つはArduinoの城です
adenocarcinoma of the lung
肺の腺癌
Then the other is to ask for Squamous Cell Cancer
次に、もう 1 つは扁平上皮がんについて尋ねることです。
on-going cells
進行中のセル
This pathology looks
この病理は次のようになります
This slice looks quite different
このスライスはかなり違うように見えます
The length is also different
長さも違います
Then this Arduino Castle
そしてこのArduino城
The reason why there are so many researches
研究がたくさんある理由
most importantly
最も重要なこと
This epidemiology found that it is this
この疫学でわかったのはこれです
female non-smoking
女性非喫煙者
especially easy to get this kind of
特にこの種のものは入手しやすい
That is to say, women do not smoke
つまり女性はタバコを吸わない
So if the doctor tells you that you have lung cancer
医師から肺がんと言われたら
The skin is definitely the fat gland
皮膚は間違いなく脂肪腺です
Very few people will get the cells of this Scramers
このスクレイマーの細胞を入手できる人はほとんどいません
It is generally believed that smoking causes cancer
一般的に喫煙はがんの原因になると考えられています
that doesn't smoke
それは喫煙しません
why cancer
なぜがんになるのか
It's still a pretty big puzzle
それにしてもかなり大きなパズルですね
that don't smoke especially women
タバコを吸わない人、特に女性
got a specific type of cancer
特定の種類のがんになった
Then his research
それから彼の研究
In medicine, that is now very popular.
医学では、それが今非常に一般的です。
Especially when he discovered a drug
特に彼が麻薬を発見したとき
is to do this with a mutation to EGF
これをEGFへの突然変異で行うことです
A mutation in a gene called EGF
EGFと呼ばれる遺伝子の変異
is a production technology
生産技術です
lower level
下層
EpDemo
エプデモ
Ghost Factor
ゴーストファクター
what is it called shrimp skin
エビの皮は何と呼ばれますか
Shrimp tissue this
エビのティッシュはこれ
to grow
成長する
factor
要素
that kind of thing
那一種東西
Mostly in the outbound cell growth
主に外向きの細胞増殖に関与
It is used a lot in fermented products
発酵食品に多く使われています
over there
そちら側
a certain one
あるもの
Nucre-Tide
ニュークレタイド
have a mutation
突然変異がある
or was deleted
または削除されました
You have a drug with that mutation
あなたはその変異を持った薬を持っています
Very effective to keep your cancer under control
がんを制御するのに非常に効果的
so
それで
the whole
全体
this
これ
above number 1
数字1の上
or treatment
または治療
a very important discovery
非常に重要な発見
That
それか
Teach them the whole of this
このすべてを彼らに教えてください
Most of this treatment of lung cancer
肺がんの治療のほとんどは
hope to do is
やりたいことは
be able to do this gine screaming first
このジンスクリーミングを最初にできるようにしてください
For example, I just mentioned that it is you if the gine
たとえば、先ほど言いましたが、ジンの場合はあなたです。
There are some legal
合法的なものもある
Then you can put the screen out
そうすれば画面を外に出すことができます
Then there is a cure
それなら治療法もあるよ
That opinion law is not the only mutation
その意見の法則だけが突然変異ではない
you may have other different mutations
他にも異なる突然変異がある可能性があります
Is that the opinionality of being able to discover other genes
それは他の遺伝子を発見できるという意見ですか？
Those structures that have mutations or mutations that are different from normal
突然変異または正常とは異なる突然変異を有する構造
Can be taken out as a target of your drag
ドラッグのターゲットとして取り出すことができます
Make something to target it with medicine
薬で狙うものを作る
Then this is currently hoping to find some drag targets
次に、これは現在、いくつかのドラッグターゲットを見つけることを望んでいます
so what
だから何
This you can do some early detection
これで早期発見ができるようになります
capable of some dalgonosis
ダルゴノーシスの可能性がある
Then mentioned many times here are all biomarkers
そして、ここで何度も言及されているのはすべてのバイオマーカーです
Biomarker is required for screen early detection
スクリーニングによる早期発見にはバイオマーカーが必要
The biomarker
バイオマーカー
What about the biomarker we used?
使用したバイオマーカーについてはどうですか?
There are so many, you can have pictures, and then you can also use the expression of this gene, microRNA
非常にたくさんあるので、写真を撮ることもできますし、この遺伝子、microRNA の発現を使用することもできます。
What about Teacher Yang's team, this
ヤン先生のチームはどうですか、これ
OK, that is BioMarket and so on, this has just been mentioned
OK、それは BioMarket などです。これは今言及したばかりです
Teacher Yang and their greatest contribution is on this day
ヤン先生と彼らの最大の貢献はこの日です
The article is on New English Medicine, the first author is Chen Xuanyi
この記事は New English Medicine に関するもので、筆頭著者は Chen Xuanyi です
Currently serving in our unit, this is his work when he was a doctoral student at National Taiwan University
現在当部隊に勤務中、これは彼が国立台湾大学の博士課程の学生だった頃の作品です
They found five genes, the five genes
彼らは5つの遺伝子を見つけた、その5つの遺伝子
What about the performance of your five genes, here
あなたの 5 つの遺伝子のパフォーマンスについては、こちらをご覧ください。
This picture shows 13 genes, about 16 genes.
この写真は 13 個の遺伝子、約 16 個の遺伝子を示しています。
Finally, they found out from these sixteen genes, and finally found out five genes
最終的に、彼らはこれら 16 個の遺伝子から発見し、最終的に 5 つの遺伝子を発見しました。
Then according to the sixteen genes
そして、16個の遺伝子によると、
In terms of genes, you can see that the expression chain is relatively high
遺伝子に関しては、発現連鎖が比較的高いことがわかります。
The higher performance chain is yellow
より高性能なチェーンは黄色です
Some genes have a higher expression chain
一部の遺伝子はより高度な発現鎖を持っています
Making other genes high is a very good performance
他の遺伝子を高くすることは非常に良いパフォーマンスです
Then according to these heights?
それでは、これらの高さに応じて？
It can do a math with the above formula
上記の式で計算できます
compress it to
に圧縮します
Then make a this to predict this
次に、これを予測するために this を作成します
It's an indicator of the patient's survival
それは患者の生存の指標です
The higher the number of months, the higher your risk
月数が長くなるほどリスクも高くなります
Then they can prove from this clinical data that
そして、この臨床データから次のことを証明できます。
What about the marker they got?
彼らが手に入れたマーカーはどうなったでしょうか？
is very effective in distinguishing between the relatively low risk
比較的リスクの低いものを区別するのに非常に効果的です
higher risk
リスクが高い
What about this picture?
この写真はどうでしょうか？
In fact, statistical biometrics
実は、統計的生体認証は、
One of the most famous pictures
最も有名な写真の 1 つ
It's called the shipping chart
送料表といいます
This picture of that CAP-CAP-MILLE
そのCAP-CAP-MILLEのこの写真
Then it reads as
すると、次のようになります
All your patients start out alive
すべての患者は最初は生きています
then learn
それから学びます
In the course of time people start dying
時間が経つにつれて人々は死に始めます
If one is not dead, he will drop one.
一人が死んでいない場合、彼は一人を落とします。
How much does it cost? This is learning to have one of this
どれくらいの費用がかかりますか? これは、これを所有することを学ぶことです
There is a formula above the statistics
統計の上に計算式があります
so fall faster
だからもっと早く落ちる
If you click more, it means your this
さらにクリックすると、これが表示されます
is a risk
リスクです
the greater the risk
リスクが大きいほど
So your low risk can hardly drop
したがって、あなたの低リスクはほとんど低下しません
high risk falls quickly
ハイリスクはすぐに落ちる
Then Teacher Yang and their results
続いてヤン先生とその結果
then come in this
それならこの中に来てください
data in the west
西側のデータ
this nature
この性質
There is a genetic medicine
遺伝子治療というものがある
2008 people this shedon
2008 人このシェドン
They also mentioned in their works
彼らも作品の中で言及しています
And then it turns out he's still just as effective
そして、彼はまだ同じくらい有能であることが判明しました
so no matter in
だから関係なく
Eastern sources in Western sources
西洋の情報源における東洋の情報源
It can also be used to do this
これを行うためにも使用できます
This none small sale cancer
この決して小さくない販売ガン
this lone cancer
これは孤独な癌です
BioMarket can be used to predict the survival of his patients
BioMarket を使用して患者の生存を予測できる
by the way SheddonLead author
by the way Sheddon第一作者
This is American is my former student at UCL
このアメリカ人はUCLの私の元生徒です
Is it actually the author's side when he does it with me?
私とやるのは実は作者側なのでしょうか？
he's just a statistician
彼はただの統計学者です
He's in Michigan now
彼は今ミシガンにいます
He can actually be the first science in Natural Medicine
彼は実際に自然医学における最初の科学になる可能性があります
This article is very good
この記事はとても良いです
He is combining about four or five large American institutions to build the Long Cancer Center.
彼は、米国の大きな機関を 4 ～ 5 つほど統合して、ロングがんセンターを建設しようとしています。
the collected data
収集されたデータ
bring it all together
全てを一つにまとめる
To see which way to predict patient survival
患者の生存を予測する方法を確認するには
which one is better
どちらがいいですか
Because stuff like suspense they do is just one way
彼らがやっているサスペンスのようなものは一方的なものだから
There are others who have different information and find out different methods
別の情報を持っていて、別の方法を見つけている人もいます
Their article is to use different marks for direct comparison
彼らの記事は、直接比較するために異なるマークを使用することです
Another job is to do what's called microsugar
もう一つの仕事は、いわゆるマイクロシュガーを行うことです
Micro ribonucleic acid is micro-init
マイクロリボ核酸はマイクロ初期です
micro-init is a little bit bigger than normal Messingale
micro-init は通常の Messingale より少し大きい
It only has about 22 nucleotides
ヌクレオチドは約 22 個しかありません
With so compact micro-init
非常にコンパクトなマイクロ初期化により、
Generally speaking, it is believed that it can be attached to some Messingale
一般的には、メッシンゲールの一部に付着できると考えられています。
The above init can destroy it or make it non-transferable
上記の初期化により、それが破壊されるか、転送不能になる可能性があります
So it has a regulatory effect on this gene
つまり、この遺伝子に調節効果があるのです
So while making a lot of Messingale like this
こうしてメッシンゲールをたくさん作りながら
In principle, it is to be translated into Protin
原則としてProtinに翻訳します。
Bringing out INA is equivalent to killing you or destroying your entire project.
INA を持ち出すことは、あなたを殺すか、プロジェクト全体を破壊することと同じです。
make you a whole can
あなたを缶丸ごとにしてください
So this MICRO-INA is very important
なのでこのMICRO-INAはとても重要です
Although it is a small tax
少額の税金ではありますが、
Tax is small, people are small, ghosts are big
稅小 人小 鬼大
According to this article
この記事によると
This is our team with that
これが私たちのチームです
Yang Panzi's team worked on this Consol Cell
Yang Panzi のチームはこのコンソール セルに取り組みました
Just find these five MICRO-INA
この 5 つの MICRO-INA を見つけてください。
and then do the same
そして同じことをします
Find a RISC score
RISC スコアを見つける
This RISC score is also based on Cox Regression here
この RISC スコアは、こちらの Cox 回帰にも基づいています
is a method of biostatistical analysis
生物統計分析の方法です
go find it this
これを探しに行ってください
The degree of influence on the survival of this certainty
この確実性の存続に及ぼす影響の程度
and then give it a different weight
そして、それに別の重みを与えます
different weight
重さが違う
Then find out a RISC score like this
次に、次のような RISC スコアを見つけます。
Then you look at the place where the RISC score is higher
次に、RISC スコアが高い場所に注目します。
This side is this time of survival
こっち側がサバイバルの時代
The same color means dead, most of the dead are more
同じ色は死んだことを意味し、死んだ人のほとんどはより多くの色を持っています
At the same time, the living time is relatively small
同時に、生存時間は比較的短いです
A little less, life is higher here
もう少し少なくても、ここでは人生はより高くなります
If the soil is like this, in fact
実は土がこんな感じだったら、
Without some statistical analysis
何らかの統計分析がなければ
Originally speaking, it was very messy at all.
もともと、とてもめちゃくちゃでした。
Then here is according to this certain order
それから、これはこの特定の順序に従っています
It must be added so that you can see it
見えるように追加する必要があります
This looks very orderly
これは非常に秩序正しく見えます
Then of course you can also put a different marker
もちろん、別のマーカーを置くこともできます
put it together
一緒に置く
For example you can put this
たとえば、これを置くことができます
Use gene expression and this micro as a combination
遺伝子発現とこのマイクロを組み合わせて利用する
can get this shipped
これを発送してもらえますか
This prediction can do better
この予測はもっとうまくいく可能性がある
OK, so to put it simply
わかりました、簡単に言うと
through life support data
生命維持データを通じて
The future theme is mainly hope from the patient
今後のテーマは主に患者様からの希望です
draw blood, etc.
採血などをします。
then go through this
それからこれを通過してください
microarray
マイクロアレイ
You just put the number of this gene
この遺伝子の番号を入力するだけです
order out
注文する
Then do some math analysis
次に、数学的な分析を行います
then you can bring
それなら持ってきてもいいよ
look at yours
あなたのものを見てください
how is the current situation
現在の状況はどうですか
It probably depends on how advanced the disease is, etc.
病気の進行度などにもよると思います。
or
また
OK
OK
good
良い
Then the many effects we just mentioned
そして、先ほど述べた多くの効果
then i want that now
それなら今すぐそれが欲しいです
make a
作る
a little summary
ちょっとした要約
Then I hope that today I can give you
それでは、今日はあなたにお届けできればと思います
There is a relatively healthy
比較的健全な状態が存在する
because I just kept saying
ずっと言い続けてたから
we can do this
できるよ
that some and every time you mention these things say
あなたがこれらのことについて言及するたびに、こう言います
There can be statistical methods and so on, and at the end it will be your result
統計的手法などがあり、最終的にはそれが結果になります
like that i think
そのように私は思います
There is no deep-rooted effect, but if I say that I want to
根強い効果はないけど、言ってみれば
All in all, there are too many companies, so
全体的に会社が多すぎるので、
I decided to just tell you guys
皆さんにだけ伝えることにしました
Some very important concepts. What about this concept?
非常に重要な概念がいくつかありますが、この概念についてはどうですか?
Can be used on this gene to behave like that
この遺伝子をそのように動作させるために使用できます
At the same time, you can also take it home and use it in your other
同時に、家に持ち帰って他の用途で使用することもできます。
life or you deal with other data above
人生、または上記の他のデータを扱う
Then I hope to be able to do something like this
そしたらこんな事ができればいいなと思っています
good
良い
Let's start from here
ここから始めましょう
Science is usually advanced and depends on some
科学は通常進歩しており、すべてが何らかのものに依存しています。
info
情報
inferences, make some inferences
推論、推論をする
These inferences are usually drawn from some already known
これらの推論は通常、すでに知られているいくつかのことから導き出されます
or partially known, to speculate on those who do not know
または部分的に知られている、知らない人に推測する
or partially know
あるいは部分的に知っている
that in this statistician
それはこの統計学者では
that they often use a method
彼らはよくある方法を使うということ
is to use some so-called this
いわゆるこれを使用することです
random, Marko-random model to
ランダム、マルコランダムモデル
is that you put each variable
各変数を入れるということです
each variable as a
各変数を
Treat it as a node like this
このようにノードとして扱います
With this, A is a variable
これにより、Aは変数になります
B is a variable
B は変数です
This R is a parameter etc.
このRはパラメータなどです。
Then this variable can control the variables below, etc.
次に、この変数は以下の変数などを制御できます。
Well, the statistics are more interesting
そうですね、統計の方が興味深いです
that's what they do
それが彼らのやることだ
a corollary that can do something like this
このようなことができる当然の結果
That is, if I talk about the variable A
つまり、変数 A について言えば、
I can get some data
ある程度のデータは取得できます
For the variable C, some data can also be obtained
変数 C についても、いくつかのデータを取得できます。
E is also available
Eも利用可能です
D is also available
Dもございます
But I don't know R and V
でもRとVは分かりません
these are my interesting
これらは私の興味深いものです
Through some so-called Bation of computation
いわゆる計算のベーションを通じて
This calculation method of Base
このBaseの計算方法は
If you already know this before and after
前後ですでにこれを知っている場合
relationship words
関係性の言葉
it can go backwards
それは後戻りする可能性があります
You can get what is the variable in this R
このRの変数が何であるかを取得できます
That
それか
But a structure like this
でもこういう構造だと
pro set is
プロセットは
First
初め
There are quite a lot of these nodes in the biological system
生体系にはこれらのノードがかなりたくさんあります
That
それか
at the same time
同時に
You know a lot
あなたはたくさん知っています
Let's say you now have 25,000 genes
現在 25,000 個の遺伝子があるとします。
You now have 25,000 nodes all know
現在 25,000 個のノードがあることがわかります
but there are many things in it
でもその中にはたくさんのものが入っています
don't even know
知りません
There will be more things I don't know
知らないことも増えるだろう
So there are many of this dimension
したがって、この次元には多くのものが存在します
some problems
いくつかの問題
how to overcome this
これをどうやって克服するか
Dimension Difficulty
Dimension的困難
On Base Computation
ベース計算
great progress so far
これまでのところ大きな進歩
Statisticians invest a lot
統計学者は多額の投資を行っている
Many so-called MCMC Algorithms
多くのいわゆる MCMC アルゴリズム
what about that part
その部分はどうですか
I won't talk about him here
ここでは彼のことは話しません
That's what I just mentioned about Macopher's
それがマコファーについて私が先ほど言ったことです
this principle
この原則
So what I want to talk about today is
それで、今日私が話したいのは、
This is the comparison
これが比較です
as a more general
より一般的なものとして
just don't need to say yes so carefully
そんなに慎重に「はい」と言う必要はありません
I have to know this identification
この識別情報を知らなければなりません
Which one to identify
どれを識別するか
what kind of relationship
どのような関係ですか
This is comparing a Generic Purpose
これは汎用品を比較しています
This is the relationship between identification and identification
これが識別と識別の関係です
I do not know anything
何も知らない
I don't need to make any assumptions
何も仮定する必要はない
then you can fetch
そうすれば取得できます
Do this to maintain the drop-down above
上のドロップダウンを維持するにはこれを実行します
It's just that I have a lot of information
ただ情報が多いだけです
But according to these common methods
しかし、これらの一般的な方法によれば、
we can reduce it to its dimension
それをその次元に縮小することができます
Comparably capable of mastering these data
これらのデータを比較的使いこなすことができる
Then there are several ways
それからいくつかの方法があります
One is Principle Component composition analysis
一つは主成分組成分析
Factor Analysis
因子分析
And then there's the division of powers and so on.
それから権限の分割などもあります。
Behind these methods
これらの手法の背後にあるもの
In fact, the most important concept is
実は、最も重要な概念は、
Correlation
相関
That's because there are many variables
それは変動要素が多いからです
So different Correlation is a lot
とても違います 相関関係はたくさんあります
Then it looks like a matrix
そうすると行列のように見えます
It is Correlation Matrix
相関行列です
Then this Correlation
次に、この相関関係
You can also look at it from another angle
別の角度から見ることもできます
It can also be regarded as similarity
類似性とも言えます
Large and polyphasic
大規模かつ多相
High Correlation indicates that the two verbals are very similar
高い相関は、2 つの言語が非常に似ていることを示します
wait
待って
ok so let's get back to this
さて、話に戻りましょう
Expression of this gene in Micro-A
Micro-Aにおけるこの遺伝子の発現
you see these bright spots
これらの明るい点が見えます
first step
最初の一歩
you need to analyze the data
データを分析する必要がある
You're going to do a lighten on this intensity
あなたはこの強さを軽くするつもりです
The lighting is very simple
照明もとてもシンプルです
That's what it's called how bright it is
どれだけ明るいかをそう呼んでいます
But the measurement of brightness is not enough
しかし、明るさの測定だけでは十分ではありません
In fact, if you put this image
実はこの画像を載せると
transfer is the expression of the gene
転移とは遺伝子の発現のことです
There are a lot of statistical
統計がたくさんある
Application service
アプリケーションサービス
how it goes
どうなるか
Because every different color has some bias
それぞれの色には偏りがあるので
There are also cases where this wavelength is different
この波長が異なる場合もあります
it will have some of this deviation
多少の偏差はあるでしょう
it is to correct
それは修正することです
Then different just above this space
次に、このスペースのすぐ上が異なります
Different points may have some deviation
異なる点には多少の誤差がある場合があります
These things have to be corrected
これらのことは修正する必要があります
Then some background noise
その後、バックグラウンドノイズが発生します
Then so this part belongs to the part of this image processing
したがって、この部分はこの画像処理の部分に属します
then more trouble
それからさらに問題が発生します
this paragraph
この段落
after processing
加工後
Usually all you have to do is
通常、あなたがしなければならないことは、
Action of Chip and Chip's Nong Ma Lai
チップとチップのノン・マーライのアクション
I am now in today's laboratory
私は今、今日の研究室にいます
make a plane
飛行機を作る
After the next five minutes, another piece of machine noodles was created
5分後、また機械麺が出来上がりました
But it is in this film and the film
しかし、それはこの映画と映画の中にあります
There is a different treatment of this
これには別の治療法があります
not saying different
違うとは言っていない
the same way
同じ方法
But the operation is always different
しかし、操作は常に異なります
Then the words inside
するとその中にある言葉が
There may be many, many factors
非常に多くの要因があるかもしれません
For example, sometimes your machine capacity is slightly different
たとえば、マシンの能力が若干異なる場合があります。
poor temperature control
温度管理が悪い
Or in this Processor
またはこのプロセッサ内で
you have to go through cleaning and so on
掃除などをしなければならない
It is quite complicated Processor
かなり複雑なプロセッサです
Any step can go wrong
どのステップでも失敗する可能性はある
From then on we often see
それからはよく見かけるようになりました
This one looks very bright
これはとても明るく見えます
That one looks less bright
そっちのほうが明るくないように見える
what about these
これらはどうですか
These require statistical methods
これらには統計的手法が必要です
to do Normalization
正規化を行うには
Now here comes the problem
ここで問題が発生します
everyone can do
誰もができる
because
なぜなら
There are too many statisticians
統計学者が多すぎる
In fact there are different teams
実は色々なチームがあるんです
Each team's words are also quite famous
各チームの言葉も有名です
For example, my former colleague is now
たとえば、私の元同僚は今、
Academician Wang Yongxiong
学者 王 永雄
Now at Stanford
今はスタンフォードにいる
They have a method called D-CHIP that must be used a lot
D-CHIPと呼ばれる方式があり、これを多用する必要があります
The other word is
もう一つの言葉は、
Terry Speed's One
テリー スピードズ ワン
that
それか
Berger Professor of Statistics
Berger的統計教授
He has a very popular method
彼は非常に人気のあるメソッドを持っています
what about different methods
さまざまな方法についてはどうですか
Everyone uses a lot but
みんなよく使ってるけど、
The trouble is this result
問題はこの結果です
the result is different
結果は異なります
Message out
メッセージアウト
tend to create
作成する傾向があります
different and that difference is quite a difference
違います、そしてその違いはかなりの違いです
so what about this
それで、これはどうですか
there is no way
道はない
The only suggestion is
唯一の提案は、
You may need to use a little more method and find out his commonality
もう少し方法を使って彼の共通点を見つける必要があるかもしれません
Then
それから
hope at a different time
別の時に希望する
According to this experiment in the next step
次のステップのこの実験によると
to determine which one would be better
どちらが良いかを判断するために
The other concept I want to tell you is that
私があなたに伝えたいもう一つのコンセプトは、
Relative amount
相対量
We hope that in fact we want to say how many votes a certain gene has
実際に、特定の遺伝子が何票持っているかを言いたいと願っています。
but this kind of thing
でもこういうこと
he is so far unfeasible
彼は今のところ実現不可能だ
there is no way to do it like this
このようにする方法はありません
Now the only thing that can be done is
今できることはただ一つ、
The relative amount is the relative amount of this gene to that one.
相対量は、その遺伝子に対するこの遺伝子の相対量です。
this thing
このこと
can be detected
検出できる
What about after this preprocessing?
この前処理の後はどうなるでしょうか？
What we got is this kind of out-of-string data is
私たちが得たものは、この種の文字列外のデータです。
Here each row represents a gene
ここで各行は遺伝子を表します
This is the gene. The first gene, the second gene, and the third gene are those light spots.
これが遺伝子で、1番目の遺伝子、2番目の遺伝子、3番目の遺伝子がその光点です。
Then
それから
listed like this
このようにリストされています
First
初め
The first column is in this
最初の列はこれにあります
The first piece, you need to make a
最初の部分を作成する必要があります。
The experiment obtained by the operation is this kind
操作して得られた実験はこんな感じ
You found a situation and got
あなたは状況を見つけて得た
It is a chip that represents a
を表すチップです。
a condition
一個 condition
is the condition
条件です
I use this below
以下でこれを使用します
This cycle of filial mother bacteria to explain
この親孝行な母菌のサイクルを説明する
This filial mother fungus in its lifetime
一生かけての親孝行な母菌
he only does one thing
彼は一つのことしかやらない
that is
あれは
In copying one cell divides into two cells
コピーすると 1 つのセルが 2 つのセルに分割されます
But this process is quite complicated
しかし、このプロセスは非常に複雑です
Filial piety mothers want to know
母親が知っておきたい親孝行
at a certain stage
ある段階で
Which genes are expressed
どの遺伝子が発現するのか
Why can it be done from one place
なぜ一か所からできるのか
which one next step
次のステップはどれですか
So there is something like this
それで、このようなものがあります
gene expression data
遺伝子発現データ
According to the data of such performance
このようなパフォーマンスのデータによると
would have been very complicated
とても複雑だったでしょう
But after the so-called
しかし、いわゆる
So Cruster's method is to group genes with the same or similar expression
したがって、クラスターの方法は、同じまたは類似した発現を持つ遺伝子をグループ化することです。
Then you will see that if it is a certain piece of A, it becomes very similar
すると、それが A の特定の部分である場合、非常に似たものになることがわかります。
And then this say this is the original part
そして、これがオリジナルの部分であると言います
Then you take the same piece of a certain piece and enlarge it
次に、ある作品の同じ部分を取り出して拡大します
You can see it and see what its gene is doing
それを見て、その遺伝子が何をしているのかを見ることができます
For example, most of this area is rival zone
例えばこのエリアのほとんどがライバルゾーンです
It is the body of the translation of the gene that we just talked about
それは今話した遺伝子の翻訳の本体です
These things make the biologist happy
これらのことは生物学者を幸せにします
He said that through these complex things that seem to have no clue
彼は、何も手がかりがないように見えるこれらの複雑な事柄を通じて、
After you line up like this
こうやって並んでから
Then it can be seen that the function of its gene is roughly the same
すると、その遺伝子の機能はほぼ同じであることがわかります。
So how does this work?
では、これはどのように機能するのでしょうか?
In case there are some genes in this piece
この作品に遺伝子が含まれている場合
It also has a different notation
違う表記もあります
I don't know, that is to say, he doesn't know his function yet.
分かりません、つまり彼は自分の役割をまだ分かっていません。
that is placed by this in the same
これによって同じに配置されます
you can go and see
行って見ることができます
Then his function is probably the same as others already known
したがって、彼の機能はおそらくすでに知られている他のものと同じです
So this is the most basic one, an application
これが最も基本的なアプリケーションです
What about this grouping method?
このグループ分け方法はどうでしょうか？
most important idea
最も重要なアイデア
that's the similarity
それが類似点です
How is the similarity obtained?
類似性はどのようにして得られるのでしょうか?
Statistically above
統計的には上
is to use the so-called correlation coefficient
いわゆる相関係数を使用することです
The correlation coefficient is used a lot in daily life
相関係数は日常生活でよく使われます
like you
あなたのような
height and weight
身長と体重
We all know that there is a proportional relationship
比例関係があることは誰もが知っています
taller, heavier
より高く、より重い
that's roughly the way it is
大体その通りです
what about sometimes
時々はどうですか
This correlation will become the inverse relationship
この相関関係は逆相関になります
Let's say your test scores
あなたのテストの点数を言ってみましょう
Questions that you answered incorrectly
間違って答えた質問
The more mistakes you make, the lower your score
ミスが多ければ多いほど、スコアは低くなります
In other cases, less obvious
その他の場合は、あまり明らかではありませんが、
For example, age and speed
たとえば、年齢やスピードなど
Age and speed are roughly the same as running five strings
年齢と速度は5本の弦を走らせるのとほぼ同じです
when you were very young
あなたがとても若かった頃
Probably the older you are, the faster you run
おそらく年をとればとるほど速く走るようになる
but when you grow old
でも年をとると
The older you get, you can't run
年を取ると走れなくなる
So the relationship is different
だから関係性が違うんだよ
Then the correlation coefficient is obtained according to a formula like this
すると、次のような式で相関係数が求められます。
Then let me dance a little here to talk about some ceremonies
それでは、ここで少し踊って、いくつかの儀式について話させてください
What about the correlation coefficient?
相関係数はどうでしょうか？
It is rarely used by mathematicians, high teachers, etc.
数学者や高等教師などが使用することはほとんどありません。
But on the statistical series
しかし統計系列に関しては
Everyone admires this guy named Gelton
誰もがゲルトンという名前の男を尊敬しています
He did a lot of interesting research during this period
彼はこの期間に多くの興味深い研究を行いました
Then he published an article
その後、彼は記事を発表しました
His article is typical low heredity
彼の記事は典型的な低遺伝性だ
Mate has a lot to do with biology
メイトは生物学と深い関係がある
Then later KL Pearson promoted his method
その後、KLピアソンが彼の手法を宣伝しました
The usual correlation we are talking about now is
私たちが今話している通常の相関関係は次のとおりです。
It turned out to be Gelton
ジェルトンだったことが判明
Scientists at Gelton's time knew pretty much everything.
ゲルトンの時代の科学者はほとんどすべてを知っていました。
Another explorer and Georgia, Mentor, etc.
別の探検家とジョージア、メンターなど。
He's a Half-Carson from Darwin
彼はダーウィン出身のハーフカーソンです
so he's very interesting about the agenda
だから彼はその議題にとても興味を持っている
One of the most important jobs he did was regulatory analysis
彼が行った最も重要な仕事の 1 つは規制分析でした
He used the relationship between the elevation of the previous generation and the next generation
彼は前世代と次の世代の標高の関係を利用しました。
He downloaded it one by one based on the information at the time
彼は当時の情報をもとにそれを一つずつダウンロードした
Then it is very hard to draw this picture
それから、この絵を描くのはとても難しいです
This diagram is the most successful part of empirical science
この図は経験科学の最も成功した部分です
He just depends on how much the rise, the rise of the father, and the rise of the children
彼はただ、父親の成長と子供たちの成長がどの程度になるかにかかっています。
appear, several times in this position
この位置で数回出現します
Such a frequency graph to deduce that
このような周波数グラフから推測できるのは、
This Distribution
このディストリビューション
It is a flower circle with the same probability of equal height
花丸と同じ高さで同じ確率で出現します
Everyone is round
みんな丸いよ
are all circles in the same direction
すべての円は同じ方向を向いています
According to this thing, it can make some mathematical inferences
このことによると、いくつかの数学的推論を行うことができます
Then add some normally distributed variables
次に、いくつかの正規分布変数を追加します
It can put the two-bit Normal Distribution
2ビットの正規分布を置くことができます
come out
出てくる
But this is a very important formula
しかし、これは非常に重要な公式です
Everyone knows that the normal distribution is that Cov is long
正規分布はCovが長いことは誰もが知っています
So it looks like a Bell
そうするとベルみたいですね
more in the middle
中間比較多
relatively few aspects
比較的少ない側面
Let's take a look at a very simple application
非常に単純なアプリケーションを見てみましょう
Here are four genes
ここに4つの遺伝子があります
Called MCM1, MCM2, MCM3, MCM4, MCM5, MCM7
MCM1、MCM2、MCM3、MCM4、MCM5、MCM7 と呼ばれます
Let's not worry about what it's doing for now
今のところ何をしているかは気にしないでください
Let's use the graph of its gene expression to see
その遺伝子発現のグラフを使って見てみましょう
look at this
これを見てください
mcm6 and mcm5
mcm6 と mcm5
What about each of these two genes?
これら 2 つの遺伝子はそれぞれどうなるのでしょうか?
Indicates that each point is a different condition
各ポイントが異なる条件であることを示します
its performance
そのパフォーマンス
So here it means that when mcm
つまり、ここでの意味は、mcm のとき
when it was high
高かったとき
When mcm6 is high, mcm7 is also high
mcm6 が高い場合、mcm7 も高くなります
when d is also d
dがdでもあるとき
So it is positively correlated
つまり正の相関がある
So mcm7 is with
だからmcm7は一緒です
mcm6 has a positive correlation with this one
mcm6 はこれと正の相関があります
5 are positively related to this
5はこれにプラスの関係があります
4 have a positive correlation
4 は正の相関がある
3 has a positive correlation, this correlation is slightly less
3 には正の相関がありますが、この相関はわずかに小さくなります
what about this
これはどうですか
Correlation is very weak
相関関係は非常に弱い
hardly relevant
ほとんど関係ない
Then take a good look at these
それから、これらをよく見てください
you will find
見つけるだろう
This mcm1 is very strange
このmcm1は非常に奇妙です
How does mcm1 relate to everyone?
mcm1はみんなとどのような関係があるのでしょうか？
are very weak
都非常弱
The other relationships are stronger.
他の関係はより強力です。
so what would you infer
それで、あなたは何を推測しますか
So 2 to 7, its functions on creatures should be more like
したがって、2から7、クリーチャーに対するその機能は次のようになります。
Then the function of MCA1 will be relatively poor
そうなると、MCA1の機能は相対的に低下します。
That's actually what it looks like
実際にそのように見えます
The role of this MCA2 is to replicate this chromosome
このMCA2の役割は、この染色体を複製することです。
It helps in the replication of chromosomes
染色体の複製を助けます
This MCA1 it is a transcription factor
このMCA1は転写因子です
is the transferred factor
転送された因子です
It is bind in front of this gene
この遺伝子の前で結合します
promoting
促進する
So the two functions are completely different
したがって、2つの機能はまったく異なります
So just relying on this simple statistic
したがって、この単純な統計に頼るだけで、
You can make an inference like this
このような推論ができます
The one I'm going to talk about next is more advanced than similarity
次にお話しするのは、類似性よりもさらに高度なものです。
higher level
より高いレベル
Then this is quite surprising
それから、これはかなり驚くべきことです
What about this concept?
このコンセプトはどうでしょうか？
it was me in 2002
それは2002年の私でした
I just started jumping into this time
今回はまだ飛び込み始めたばかりです
I find
見つけました
At that time a lot of people have done a lot of things
あの頃はいろんな人がいろんなことをやってたな
like this Crossing
この交差点のように
everyone did
誰もがやった
then i was thinking
それから私は考えていました
what am i doing here
私はここで何をしているんだ
Is there anyone who already knows
すでに知っている人はいますか
Everyone can use computer
誰もがコンピュータを使用できる
then i will think about some
それからいくつか考えてみます
Is there still fish in the meat net?
肉網の中にはまだ魚が入っていますか？
There are some ideas
いくつかのアイデアがあります
Everyone hasn't thought of it yet
みんなまだ考えてないよ
but don't be too responsible
でもあまり責任を持たないでください
because you talk to the school of life
あなたは人生の学校と話すから
Or what, you talked too complicated all at once
というか、一度に複雑な話をしすぎた
they can't accept
彼らは受け入れられない
Then there will be some in the middle
そうすれば真ん中にもいくつかあるでしょう
There are some gaps
多少の隙間はありますが
Then I hope to find a very simple solution
それから、非常に簡単な解決策が見つかることを願っています
but there's still something you can do
でもまだできることはある
Let everyone unexpected at the same time
誰もが同時に予想外のことをしましょう
Is it possible to convince the school of life that
人生の学校に次のことを納得させることができるだろうか。
also useful
也有用
Then this article is here
それではこの記事はこちらです
that PNS
そのPNS
that is
あれは
The PNS above in 2002
上面2002年的PNS
post below
以下に投稿します
then i
その後私は
Because just now the dean and the vice dean also mentioned that I was born in the Department of Mathematics
だって、さっき学部長も副学部長も言ってたけど、私は数学科の出身なんです。
in college
大学で
What we often ask in mathematics is a logical relationship
数学でよく問われるのは論理関係です
if a then b
aならb
if a holds
a が成立する場合
This b is established if this is a true statement
これが真であれば、この b が成立します。
Then its counter-narrative may not be correct
そうなると、その反論は正しくないかもしれない
If b is right, you may not be right about a
b が正しい場合、a については正しくない可能性があります。
This is a logically important concept
これは論理的に重要な概念です
So ask a question like this
そこでこのような質問をしてください
Just now we know that your two genes have a high degree of similarity
たった今、あなたの 2 つの遺伝子が高度な類似性を持っていることが分かりました
Then we biologists focus on its biological function
そこで私たち生物学者はその生物学的機能に焦点を当てます
will be more or less the same
多かれ少なかれ同じでしょう
So one question I ask is
そこで私が尋ねる質問の 1 つは、
If two genes are related
2つの遺伝子が関連している場合
is very similar
とても似ています
ok that ok
わかりました、大丈夫です
you two on this creature
あなたたち二人はこの生き物について
it's related to genes that act a lot like
それはよく似た働きをする遺伝子に関係している
it's this expression it's the expression
それはこの表現です、それはこの表現です
Is the degree of belief very high?
信仰度はかなり高いのでしょうか？
i repeat
繰り返します
What we saw earlier is
先ほど見たのは
If it is two genes, its expression is above
2つの遺伝子の場合、その発現は上記になります
its similarity is high
その類似性は高いです
Biologists will accept that it functions above
生物学者はそれが上記で機能することを受け入れるでしょう
There is a fair chance it will be the same
同じになる可能性は十分にあります
or similar
または類似
What we are now asking is the opposite
私たちが今求めているのはその逆です
That is, two genes are related in the same way.
つまり、2 つの遺伝子は同じように関連しています。
participating in the same function
同じ行事に参加している
It's on this gene expression
それはこの遺伝子発現に関係しています
Will it be that there is often a great degree of similarity
多くの場合、かなりの程度の類似性が存在するということになるだろうか
that answer is wrong
その答えは間違っています
It's because of our genes
それは私たちの遺伝子のせいです
its regulation
その規制
it's too complicated
複雑すぎます
My first Ns is of course that micro-ray is too noisy
私の最初のNsは、もちろんマイクロレイがうるさすぎるということです
but noise is another matter
しかし、騒音は別の問題です
Because of the regulation of your gene
遺伝子の調節のせいで
is a very complex structure
非常に複雑な構造です
So while two genes are participating in the same industry
したがって、2 つの遺伝子が同じ産業に参加している間、
Because there are many external factors interfering there
そこには多くの外的要因が干渉するため、
so your words won't be consistent
だからあなたの言葉には一貫性がなくなる
Here are some reasons for the list
リストの理由は次のとおりです
do i think i'll just skip this part
この部分は飛ばしてもいいと思いますか？
don't talk about it
それについては話さないでください
in fact
実際には
on a further molecular level
さらに分子レベルで
There is also a phenomenon
という現象もあります
I'm here to say quickly
早く言いたいのでここに来ました
That is, your genes fall into the so-called Histone
つまり、あなたの遺伝子はいわゆるヒストンに分類されます。
the so-called main protein
いわゆるメインタンパク質
you are some chromosomes
あなたはいくつかの染色体です
Then
それから
So it by itself suppresses the expression of this gene
したがって、それ自体がこの遺伝子の発現を抑制します
You need to open this thing first
まずこれを開く必要があります
make it not wrapped in
包まれないようにする
You can have genetic expression
遺伝子を発現させることができる
So there's a gene here
つまりここに遺伝子があるのです
There is a transcription factor
転写因子がある
it works weird
それは奇妙に動作します
even if it is a repressor
たとえそれがリプレッサーであっても
is also an activator
活性剤でもあります
what is repressor
リプレッサーとは何ですか
its turn factor
そのターンファクター
it suppresses gene expression
遺伝子発現を抑制する
activator is just the opposite
アクティベーターはその逆です
But in some cases it can do both
ただし、場合によっては両方を実行できる場合もあります
The reason why it can do both
両方できる理由
It turns out that there are other factors at work
他の要因が作用していることが判明
This example is a pretend finite number
この例は擬似的な有限数です
This pretends to limit this Harm to do its job
これは、この害がその役割を果たせるように制限するふりをします
It has a structure without pretending to be limited
限定を装わない構造になっている
There are pretending to limit the number of its structures to change
変更する構造の数を制限するふりをしています
so we often say
だから私たちはよく言います
a certain turn factor
特定の回転率
It is positively regulated
積極的に規制されている
a turn factor
回転率
attached regulation
附則
This way of speaking is too five paragraphs
この話し方は5段落多すぎます
Some of these regulators
これらの規制当局の一部
There are forward and reverse
順方向と逆方向があります
that controls whether it is forward or bidirectional
順方向か双方向かを制御します
are some other extrinsic factors
他の外部要因です
Now here comes the problem
ここで問題が発生します
these extrinsic factors
これらの外的要因
how do we know
どうやって知ることができますか
the biologist
生物学者
he because
彼はなぜなら
many things are sprouting
いろんなものが芽吹いてる
limited knowledge
限られた知識
so he doesn't know
だから彼は知らない
Then ask our ruler
それから私たちの支配者に尋ねてください
more laymen
もっと素人
how do you know
どうして知っていますか
you don't know of course i don't know
あなたはもちろん知りません、私も知りません
then i
その後私は
but i just told you
でも私はあなたに言ったばかりです
what about statisticians
統計学者はどうですか
something mathematicians are not afraid of
数学者が恐れていないもの
is that we can make some assumptions
いくつかの仮定を立てることができるということです
we want to start from position
ポジションから始めたいと思います
there is something from the chair
椅子から何かあります
or part chair
または部分椅子
we go to test the location of things
物の位置をテストしに行きます
made some models
いくつかのモデルを作りました
So let's make an adult's assumption here
ここで大人の推測をしてみましょう
OK, if the gene
OK、遺伝子なら
with the things it regulates
それが規制するものに関して
in a certain state
ある状態で
it has positive
それはポジティブです
It is a
それは
positive transfer
正の転移
then in another state
その後、別の状態で
it has a reverse feed
逆送りがある
But I control this turn
でもこのターンは私がコントロールする
The forward or reverse of these timbres
これらの音色の順方向または逆方向
I have no idea
何も思いつきません
But I make an assumption
しかし、私は仮定を立てます
Say this, these sound quality, or this state
こう言う、この音質とか、この状態とか。
will be on a certain pitch
特定のピッチに立つだろう
will be shown
表示されます
it's just an assumption
それは単なる仮定です
So in this different this
それで、これはこれとは異なります
For example, when Hormono
例えばホルモンのとき
This State 1
この状態1
its fundamental tone it doesn't show
その基本的なトーンが表示されない
But when there is less hormonal
でもホルモンが少ないと
This pitch is more than expressed
このピッチは表現以上のものです
then i can
それならできます
There is a hypothesis like this
こんな仮説があります
I don't need to know that it's hormonal that affects this
これに影響を与えるのがホルモンであることを知る必要はありません
I just need to know that it affects it
それが影響するということだけ知っていればいい
Just a certain pitch
特定のピッチだけ
Although this thing is the most important
これが一番大事なのに
but its performance
しかしそのパフォーマンス
So I make an assumption like this
そこで私はこんな推測をします
So through a situation like this
ですから、このような状況を経て、
In addition to saying that the pitch and its
ピッチとその
This is a transfer sound quality
転送音質です
This is the pitch of its regulation
これが規制の主旨です
It is sometimes a positive regulation
ポジティブな規制となる場合もある
negative regulation
ネガティブな規制
but you not only
しかしあなただけではありません
Knowing this is true, you would think
これが真実だと知ったら、あなたはこう思うでしょう。
he doesn't matter
彼は関係ない
But if you say that through this third gene
でも、この第三の遺伝子を通してそう言うなら
When your third gene doesn't express
3番目の遺伝子が発現しないとき
all green
すべて緑色
just these times
ちょうどこの頃
If it's red, that's all
赤くなったらそれで終わり
So it's a very simple concept
非常に単純な概念です
that's how it behaves
それがそのように動作します
But it's so dark here that it's us
でもここはとても暗いので、そこは私たちです
can't be the same
同じことはできない
Previously it was only necessary to link two genes to see how similar they were
以前は、2 つの遺伝子をリンクするだけで、それらがどの程度類似しているかを確認できました。
That now turns into studying three genes
それは今度は 3 つの遺伝子を研究することになります
That's X, Y, Z
それがX、Y、Zです
that's more complicated
それはもっと複雑です
What is the level of complexity?
複雑さのレベルはどれくらいですか?
we are doing
私たちはやっています
Like the example just now, when making filial mother fungus
先ほどの例のように、親孝行な母菌を作るときは
Probably around 6,000 genes
おそらく遺伝子は約6,000個ある
Of the 6,000 genes you have to take three
6,000 個の遺伝子のうち 3 つを取得する必要があります
thirty eight
三十八
This is 5878
こちらは5878です
Counting is 33.8 triplets of point B
カウンティングはB点の3連符33.8個です
That's too much
それは多すぎます
If the quantity is too large
量が多すぎる場合
I can't say a triplet
三つ子とは言えない
Just use the priest method just now to look at his relationship
先ほどの司祭の方法を使って彼の関係を見てみましょう
I must
私はしなければならない
Provide a statistic for the computer to calculate
コンピュータが計算する統計を提供します
What about the amount?
金額についてはどうですか？
How did you recruit them?
どのようにして彼らを採用したのですか？
I inferred from some of these mathematical statistics
これらの数学的統計のいくつかから推測しました
I'm sorry about this
この件については申し訳ありません
i'm just here
私はここにいるだけです
It's just like show off
まるで見せびらかしてるようなものだ
Just a reference
あくまで参考です
So after some statistics, some definitions above, etc.
したがって、いくつかの統計や上記の定義などを踏まえた上で、
found that under such circumstances
そのような状況下で発見した
there is a nice formula
素敵な公式があります
You can use this to calculate this
これを使用してこれを計算できます
The formula is simply
式は単純に
x1 y1 z1
x1 y1 z1
cover up
隠ぺいする
multiply up add up
掛け算 足し算
What is x1 y1 z1 x2 y2 z2
x1 y1 z1 x2 y2 z2 とは何ですか
That is, the three genes are different
つまり、3つの遺伝子は異なるということです。
Performance under condition
条件下でのパフォーマンス
so very simple
とてもシンプルです
in a certain state
ある状態で
how much the first gene is expressed
最初の遺伝子がどの程度発現されるか
how much the second gene is expressed
2番目の遺伝子がどの程度発現されるか
how much the first three genes express
最初の 3 つの遺伝子がどれだけ発現するか
just ride it up
ただそれに乗って
everyone will be punished
誰もが罰を受けるだろう
in the second case
2番目の場合
add it up too
それも加算してください
So all your data adds up like this
すべてのデータを合計すると次のようになります
This is my consideration
これは私の考察です
Then this example is called liquid association
この例は液体会合と呼ばれます
Liquid association is a relatively abstract concept
液体結合は比較的抽象的な概念です
It is mainly used to describe
主に説明するために使用されます
this
これ
correlation
相関
will be like
のようになるでしょう
Liquids flow like water
液体は水のように流れる
Sometimes it's positive, sometimes it's negative
ポジティブなときもあれば、ネガティブなときもある
there will be this fluttering
これがはためくでしょう
image
画像
What about a formula like this?
このような式はどうでしょうか？
In fact, it is equivalent to a
実際、それは次のものと同等です。
Fissure yes correlation a generalization
亀裂あり、相関関係あり、一般化あり
Fissure i fissure is arguably the most famous statistician in the world
Fissure i fissure はおそらく世界で最も有名な統計学者です
That
それか
Yes, it is also looking for a very important statistician
はい、非常に重要な統計学者も探しています
then they
それから彼らは
When doing this correlation before, he didn’t follow the same route as Pearlson
以前にこの相関関係を行ったとき、彼はパールソンと同じルートをたどりませんでした
he is
彼は
Do say I just put this first each
これをそれぞれ最初に置くだけだと言ってください
Statistics first make it a normal score transformation first normalize it
統計はまず正規スコア変換を行い、次に正規化します。
then you
次にあなた
After normalizing it
正規化してから
I want to calculate his two correlation is very simple
彼の 2 つの相関関係を計算したいのですが、非常に簡単です
It's fine if the two inherit each other.
両者が継承していれば大丈夫です。
this is their method
これが彼らのやり方です
This method has its benefits
この方法には利点があります
it for those
それは彼らのためです
The so-called Outline
いわゆるアウトライン
Sometimes the data is messy
データが乱雑になる場合がある
some words jump especially big
一部の単語は特に大きくジャンプします
This method will not be so Sensitive
この方法はそれほどセンシティブではありません
can limit
制限できる
my method
私の方法
almost equal to this replica of it
このレプリカとほぼ同等
add an extra gene
余分な遺伝子を追加する
But the math behind it is completely different.
しかし、その背後にある数学はまったく異なります。
so that's
だから〜だ
I'll do a little math for the benefit
利益のために少し計算してみます
So here is the Normal distribution
これが正規分布です
how did it work
それはどうでしたか？
back to this
これに戻って
This example of filial mother
この親孝行な母親の例
let me tell you one
一つ言わせてください
only one application
アプリケーションは 1 つだけ
Because what I said today is that there are several applications left
今日私が言ったのは、いくつかのアプリケーションが残っているということです
But maybe I'm not here because of time
でも時間の関係でここにいないのかもしれない
keep talking about this app
このアプリについて話し続けます
this application
このアプリ
looks very complicated
とても複雑に見えます
actually
実際
you know other results
他の結果はご存知ですか
The secret is actually quite simple
その秘密は実はとてもシンプルです
This is a
これは
path of chemical reaction
化学反応の経路
Its main purpose is to illuminate the Aquini
その主な目的はアクィニを照らすことです。
This Aquini is crystal dark acid
このアキニはクリスタルダークアシッドです
It is a series of chemical reactions
一連の化学反応です
Every chemical reaction involves an enzyme
すべての化学反応には酵素が関与します
Its original source is from ancient times
その起源は古くからある
Gutmey is blessing dark acid
ガトメイはダークアシッドを祝福しています
Through this ARG2 enzyme
このARG2酵素を介して
ARG2 is this synthetic beauty
ARG2はこの合成美です
And then make this called Osli Bird Dark Sour
そして、これを「オスリバードダークサワー」と名付けます。
and then after here
そしてこの後
Its chemical reaction is going this way
化学反応はこうやって進む
If you come here, the next step is to become this Psytrillion
ここに来たら次はこのサイトリリオンになる
is hanging dark acid
ダークアシッドをぶら下げています
Then wait until the end to get Crystal Dark Acid
その後、最後まで待ってクリスタルダークアシッドを入手してください
When your crystal dark acid if too much
クリスタルダーク酸が多すぎる場合
it will be broken down again
また壊れるだろう
This breaks down into
これは次のように分類されます
back to this bird dark sour
この鳥に戻る ダークサワー
So this is a cycle
これがサイクルです
This is quite effective
これはかなり効果的です
Because this has uria cycle
これは尿周期があるので
word from here
ここからの言葉
After this crystal dark acid is decomposed
この結晶が分解された後、暗色の酸が生成されます。
will run deep in this uria
この尿の奥深くまで走ります
So what about the loop
では、ループはどうでしょうか
Although on filial mother fungi
親孝行な母菌ですが
The same is true for the human body and the kidneys
人間の体や腎臓も同様です
is a very important mechanism
非常に重要なメカニズムです
Then if you look at a picture like this
それで、このような写真を見ると、
look at these chemical reactions
これらの化学反応を見てください
how do i know
どうやって知ることができますか
But this is very certain
しかし、これは非常に確実なことです
imagine these chemical reactions
これらの化学反応を想像してください
In fact, it is like a string of processing factories.
実際、加工工場が連なっているようなものです。
so stuff comes in
それで物が入ってくる
I just parse it
ただ解析するだけです
So let's say
それで言ってみましょう
when you want to take this thing
これを取りたいとき
this thing must have
これは必ずあるはずだ
So the more this thing
だから、これが多ければ多いほど
I will show more of this thing
このことをもっと見せます
But my goal is to follow this
しかし、私の目標はこれに従うことです
So if say this CR2
つまり、この CR2 を言うと
nuclease
ヌクレアーゼ
have something
何かを持っています
also expressed a lot of words
たくさんの言葉も表現しました
Then this Ostiny thing
それからこのオスティニーのこと
Will it be broken down immediately?
すぐに壊れてしまうのでしょうか？
Then it would be wrong to do false work for nothing.
ならば、無償で偽りの仕事をするのは間違いだろう。
So you'd guess that yes
だからあなたはそう思うでしょう
When ARG2 it expresses high
ARG2の場合は高さを表現します
When the synthetic surface is high
合成表面が高い場合
this thing shouldn't exist
こんなものは存在すべきではない
It should express less
表現は少なくするべきです
Otherwise, you just go in
それ以外の場合は、ただ入ってください
It will be digested immediately, and it will be a waste of work
すぐに消化されて無駄な作業になる
So you would speculate that the relationship between these two
したがって、これら 2 つの関係は次のように推測されます。
should be related
関連するはずです
This is higher and this is lower
これは高くて、これは低いです
Then let's see if Data looks like this
次に、データが次のようになっているかどうかを確認してみましょう
Sorry, this jumps a few pages first
申し訳ありませんが、最初に数ページジャンプします
I'll come back to this later
これについては後で説明します
Let's look at Data first
まずはデータを見てみましょう
This data is for everyone not to look at these two lines
このデータは皆さんにこの 2 行を見ないようにしてください
Also don't look at these red dots or different colors
また、これらの赤い点や異なる色を見ないでください。
Every point is a data point
すべての点はデータ ポイントです
This information is from what we just talked about
この情報は私たちが今話した内容からのものです
The information on Sale Cycle
セールサイクルのご案内
Exactly the same but I use it to study different things
まったく同じですが、別のことを勉強するために使用しています
You said oh oh, check to see if there is anything related
あなたは、ああ、何か関連があるかどうか見てくださいと言った
It cannot be positively correlated without correlation
相関関係がなければ正の相関関係はあり得ません
If it is positively correlated, it should look like this
正の相関がある場合は、次のようになります。
Direct phase is not reverse
正相は逆ではない
Not reverse is no correlation
逆ではないということは相関関係がないということです
that's not relevant
それは関連性がありません
Then we just speculated that
それから私たちは次のように推測しました
Just now I speculated that it was these two, if so
もしそうなら、それはこの二人だろうと推測しただけですが、
Cell needs RNG saying these two should have a negative correlation
セルには、これら 2 つには負の相関があるはずであるという RNG が必要です
why didn't that
なぜそうしなかったのか
Then I said ok then it's okay
それから私は「わかりました、それで大丈夫です」と言いました
Then maybe if the cells disappear forever, it will be RNG
じゃあ細胞が永久に消えたらRNGになるかもね
Not called RGN
RGNとは呼ばれません
it maybe sometimes it doesn't need
場合によっては必要ないかもしれない
how do i know
どうやって知ることができますか
How do I know when it's needed and when it's not
いつ必要で、いつ必要ではないかをどうやって知ることができますか
Then I will use this liquid manual to learn how to use it
次に、この液体マニュアルを使用してその使用方法を学びます
My hypothesis is that maybe at some point it will
私の仮説は、おそらくある時点でそうなるだろうということです
maybe it doesn't
たぶんそうではない
what time does it want
何時ですか
Maybe some of the elite will be shown when it wants to
おそらく、望むときにエリートの一部が表示されるでしょう
which elites
どのエリートが
how could I know
どうやって知ることができたでしょうか
I don't know it's okay
大丈夫か分からない
find one by one
一つ一つ見つけて
so how do i find it
それで、どうやって見つければいいですか
this is me
これが私です
I take this thing as x
私はこれを x とみなします
This thing is regarded as y, so there is no
これは y とみなされますので、
without that
それがなければ
correlation so it is
相関関係そうだね
To count this liquid association
この液体結合を数えるには
For each gene, there are about 6,000 genes in total, and each one is counted, so the basic calculation is not too big
各遺伝子には合計約 6,000 個の遺伝子があり、それぞれがカウントされるため、基本的な計算はそれほど大きくありません
then arrange it
それからそれを手配する
and then went to see its largest and found
それから最大のものを見に行き、見つけました
The eighth largest here is the small
ここで8番目に大きいのは小さいものです
this
これ
negative biggest
負的最大的
Find this gene as soon as you look for it, that's good because there are 6,000 genes
遺伝子は 6,000 個あるので、探したらすぐに見つかります。
The eighth is around here
8番目はこのあたりです
so this
したがって、この
It can be said that it was hit
当たったと言える
hit
打つ
Not only that
それだけでなく
Here it is, if you look more closely
よく見てみるとこうです
But you can see that when the CPA is
しかし、CPA が
when performance is high
パフォーマンスが高いとき
it has a negative correlation
それは負の相関関係があります
The negative correlation we want is when
私たちが求める負の相関は、次のような場合です。
CPA is when performance is high
CPAはパフォーマンスが高いときの値です
When the CPA performance is small it is
CPA パフォーマンスが小さい場合は、
multiply positive correlation
正の相関を乗算する
Is this relationship reasonable?
この関係は合理的ですか?
let's look back
振り返ってみましょう
What does it mean when this gene is expressed high?
この遺伝子の発現量が多いということは何を意味するのでしょうか?
If this thing is high, it can take this Gutmin
これが高ければ、このガットミンもかかります
Decomposition then yields this
分解するとこれが得られます
This metabolite of Carbomile phosphate
このカルボマイルリン酸の代謝物
What about this metabolite?
この代謝物はどうでしょうか？
Can Oscling with this
これでオスリングできますか
Through this ARG this synthesis
このARGを通じてこの合成は
to synthesize this
これを合成するには
so
それで
When this you do RG0
これを実行するとRG0
Right and wrong need not only Oscling
善悪はオスリングだけでは必要ない
At the same time you also need this Carbomile
同時にこのカーボマイルも必要です
Then you need Carbomile
それならカルボマイルが必要だ
It's about to come out. If you don't have this synthesis, you won't have it.
そろそろ出てきますが、この合成が無いと出ません。
so
それで
My explanation is that when the composition does not show
私の説明では、構図が表示されない場合は、
It will represent that the cell needs RG0
これは、セルに RG0 が必要であることを意味します。
When the cell needs RG0
セルが RG0 を必要とする場合
ARG2 is just negatively correlated with CR2
ARG2 は CR2 と負の相関があるだけです
So this is completely represented by our picture
これは私たちの写真によって完全に表現されています
Another situation is when CR2 does not perform
もう 1 つの状況は、CR2 が実行されない場合です。
It happens to be DR's WareRound
それはたまたま DR の WareRound です
just another situation
ちょうど別の状況
That is, when there is no here, it means that there is no need here
つまり、ここがないということは、ここには必要がないということです
those are the times when you don't need it
そういう時はそれが必要ない時だよ
In that case, it means that the cell
その場合、それは細胞が
Maybe this arginic acid is too much
もしかしたらこのアルギン酸が多すぎるのかもしれません
If there is too much arginic acid, it will break down
アルギン酸が多すぎると分解してしまう
So when you want to decompose this thing should show
したがって、分解したいときは、これが表示されるはずです
So when you are still tall
だからまだ背が高いときは
If your stuff is not high
荷物が高くない場合
that's bad
それは良くないね
It will also be forced on this may produce more
また、これにより強制的にさらに多くのことが発生する可能性があります
So the best solution is when this high
したがって、最善の解決策は、これが高いときです
The god you produce is digested immediately
あなたが生み出した神はすぐに消化されます
broken down
壊れた
Use CR2 performance to decompose it
CR2の性能を利用して分解する
So this is a rather subtle
したがって、これはかなり微妙です
right here
ここにあります
The enzymes in the shells that we often eat
私たちがよく食べる貝殻に含まれる酵素
Inside a little angry bag
少し怒っているバッグの中
by the expression of this gene
この遺伝子の発現によって
complicated inside
複雑な内部
6000 genes inside
6000個の遺伝子が入っている
Let's watch these
これらを見てみましょう
It's all in this picture
この写真にすべてが詰まっています
Then you look out and see it's totally irrelevant
それから外を見ると、それはまったく無関係であることがわかります
But you should use statistical methods well
ただし、統計的手法をうまく活用する必要があります
go
行く
From what is already known to infer some positions
すでに知られていることからいくつかの位置を推測する
Can find a quite reasonable explanation
かなり合理的な説明が見つかる
Then this method can be used a lot
それならこの方法は色々使えますね
means you have two genes
2つの遺伝子を持っていることを意味します
I'm going to find a third gene that regulates these two
この 2 つを制御する 3 つ目の遺伝子を見つけ出すつもりです
there is a way
やり方がある
That can also be said in reverse
それは逆にも言えます
I one I can start with a gene
私は遺伝子から始めることができる
See which genes it can regulate
どの遺伝子を調節できるかを確認する
wait
待って
Then this method can also be extended to
この方法は次のように拡張することもできます。
more genes above
さらに上の遺伝子
That uses some other math
それは他の数学を使用します
Are these just for reference?
これらは単なる参考ですか?
that's in this
それはこの中にあります
ah early words
ああ、早い言葉
ah for publication
ああ、出版のため
During the paper period, I went to find some
論文期間中、私はいくつかのものを探しに行きました
this on the gene
これは遺伝子上で
Information
情報
and found
そして、見つけた
there is a group
有一組
The information can be brought here
データはこちらから持ち込めます
do some of this
これのいくつかをやってください
Ah, the research on human genes
ああ、人間の遺伝子の研究
According to that information
その情報によると
ah
ああ
At that time, for some reason
その時、なぜか
Special interest in dementia
認知症に特に興味がある
then read some books
それから本を何冊か読んでください
then just
それからちょうど
ah see some of this
ああ、これの一部を見てください
major gene
主要な遺伝子
that is
あれは
ah on top of this
ああ、この上に
I just saw some black ones that are called
と呼ばれる黒いものをいくつか見たところです
amino acid beta peptide
アミノ酸βペプチド
this thing is made of
これはでできています
a large protein
一個大的 protein
After two of this chemical this
この化学薬品を 2 回摂取した後、
Enzyme changes, this
酵素が変わる、ああこれ
7. I just feel that I can use the lump at the bottom to compare
7. 一番下の塊を使って比較できるような気がします
want
欲しい
show it
それを示す
That's the big one
それが一番大きいです
This red part is
この赤い部分は、
This is what caused your brain age
これがあなたの脳老化の原因です
eat the most important ingredient
最も重要な食材を食べる
Then this ingredient needs to be cut by two enzymes
次に、この成分は2つの酵素によって切断される必要があります
Then one by one
それから一つ一つ
just on the left
ちょうど左側にある
Then a knife is on the right
そうすると右側にナイフがあります
Those two are two different enzymes
これら 2 つは異なる酵素です
good
良い
That
それか
Then the APP’s role in general physiology
次に、一般的な生理機能における APP の役割
Actually it's not clear
実際のところは明らかではない
Then in 2001
そして2001年に
it was me just then
ちょうどその時は私でした
Really like this liquid phone
このリキッドフォンが本当に気に入りました
When I first started researching
私が初めて研究を始めたとき
This paper just came out
この論文はちょうど出たばかりです
Then what
じゃあ何
it's taken from some chemistry experiments
それはいくつかの化学実験から取られたものです
It found this APP?
このアプリを見つけましたか？
with these two proteins
この2つのタンパク質を使って
were caught together at the same time
同時に捕まった
They use a
彼らは、
a kind of that
それの一種
It's like saying you're going to commit a crime first.
犯罪を先に犯すと言っているようなものだ。
he opened the cell
彼は独房を開けた
then make some discoveries
それからいくつかの発見をしてください
found this thing combined with him
これが彼と組み合わされているのを見つけました
This thing is combined with him
これは彼と組み合わされています
if that thing is put together
それがまとまっていれば
I would deduce that he should have
私は彼がそうすべきだったと推測します
Fang Xiong should have related
Fang Xiong は何か関連するものを持っているはずです
Fangxiong related words
方雄に関連した言葉
on the expression of this gene
この遺伝子の発現について
not necessarily relevant
必ずしも関連性があるわけではない
because i this is my original subject
私はこれが私の本来の主題だから
then he is
それなら彼は
Correlation is indeed very little
確かに相関関係は非常に小さい
His correlation is very little
彼の相関関係は非常に少ない
so i say
だから私は言います
Then this is EH maybe use liquid
それから、これは EH たぶん液体を使用します
The method learned
学んだ方法
So I put this APP
そこでこのAPPを入れました
When X and Y are regarded as one of them
XとYを片方とみなした場合
Then
それから
Here is the human body
ここが人間の体です
So this whole gold probably
つまり、この金全体はおそらく
At that time their gold piece
そのとき彼らの金貨
technology limitation
技術的limitation
probably made almost ten thousand
おそらく1万近く稼いだ
So just the same job
つまり同じ仕事
one to find those related
関連するものを見つけるためのもの
first to find this
まずこれを見つけます
PSEN
PSEN
this is the code
これがコードです
this
これ
oops , a little too fast
おっと、ちょっと速すぎる
you want to go back
戻りたいですか
Sorry, one of them may have been skipped
申し訳ありませんが、そのうちの 1 つがスキップされた可能性があります
OK, that one dropped in the second place
OK、あれは2位に落ちました
That is to say, simply explain
つまり簡単に説明すると
this
これ
what about my result
私の結果はどうですか
It's in that very high ranking
かなり上位にランクインしてますね
just found this
これを見つけたばかりです
it has related this
それはこれに関係しています
PSAN
PSAN
then this thing is
これは
Gama Security
ガマセキュリティ
what about the other one
もう一つはどうですか
same, good
同じ、良い
This X, that's another
このX、あれは別のXです
was caught at the same time as it
それと同時に捕まった
then go to see
それから見に行きます
The result you see is this
表示される結果はこれです
Base 2, that is
基数 2、つまり
Veta Side's APP
ベータサイドのAPP
Cricked Entire
全体がひび割れた
Simple explanation, just use this method
簡単な説明、この方法を使うだけです
it's ingenious
それは独創的です
That is, in 10,000 manager heads
つまり、10,000 人のマネージャーの頭の中では
Use this XY to find
この XY を使用して見つけます
I found out that it happened to be these two audio loaders.
たまたまこの 2 つのオーディオ ローダーであることがわかりました。
Its score is very high
そのスコアは非常に高いです
And then down here is an app
そして、ここにアプリがあります
That's because there is a doctor
医者がいるからだよ
I know that at UCL
UCLではそれを知っています
this postdoc
このポスドク
He is from Human Genetic
彼はヒューマンジェネティック出身です
he sees these results
彼はこれらの結果を見ます
he is very interested
彼はとても興味があります
So I found his instructor
そこで私は彼のインストラクターを見つけました
Come and discuss with me
来て私と話し合ってください
Then his team is right about this
それなら彼のチームはこれに関して正しい
Multiple Sclerosis
多発性硬化症
polymorphism
多態性
very interested
興味深い
the european white
ヨーロッパの白人
This specifies a lot
これは多くのことを指定します
Then it's a Neuron's this
じゃあニューロンはこれだ
Simply put, the immune system
簡単に言えば、免疫システム
this cell that is attacking this nerve
この神経を攻撃しているこの細胞
put this outside this
これをこの外に置きます
The Mining of the students
学生たちの採掘
persecuted it
それを迫害した
so he starts this
それで彼はこれを始めます
there are some scars coming out
多少の傷跡が出てきています
Then it recurs after a while
その後しばらくすると再発します
that's usually looking for the gene
それは通常、遺伝子を探している
Generally, it is the route of Genovice
大体ジェノヴィツェのルートです
That is, where do you go to see people doing some Genovice
つまり、ジェノヴィスをやっている人を見るにはどこに行きますか？
at that time i was
そのとき私は
Learning while doing Liquid
Liquidをやりながら学ぶ
So what is used is a quite different method from ordinary people.
つまり、常人とは全く異なる手法が使われているのです。
What was used at that time was
その時に使われていたのが、
This data is completely Geneexpression data
このデータは完全に Geneexpression データです
Not this marker data
このマーカー データではありません
gene expression data
遺伝子発現データ
At the same time, these Geneexpression data
同時に、これらの Geneexpression データ
It has nothing to do with this Multiple Sclerosis
多発性硬化症とは関係ありません
this one is
これは
researching this
これを研究している
i-Zen is different from i-C8
i-Zenはi-C8とは異なります
Then additionally these data are
さらに、これらのデータは
looking at the different organs of the body
体のさまざまな器官を観察する
expression of these genes
これらの遺伝子の発現
how to be different
どのように違うのか
These data are completely unrelated to Multiple
これらのデータはマルチプルとはまったく無関係です
And what about the MVP?
そしてMVPはどうなるでしょうか？
is a gene
遺伝子です
it is
それはです
It is the cell in this Mining
それがこの鉱山の細胞です
In the outer layer of nerve cells, there are many manifestations
神経細胞の外層にはさまざまな症状が現れます
So it's a very important Proton
とても重要なプロトンです
So take it as X
したがって、それを X とします
what is Y
Yとは何ですか
Y is provided by our collaborators
Y は協力者によって提供されます
They were very interested in this gene at the time
彼らは当時この遺伝子に非常に興味を持っていました
Because they are this difficult TIN
とても難しい TIN なので
where he found
彼が見つけた場所
After some genetics above this Typing
これ以上の遺伝学を入力した後、
It was found that this gene is likely to be related to this Multiple Sclerosis
この遺伝子が多発性硬化症に関連している可能性が高いことが判明しました。
So he just provided the gene
つまり彼は遺伝子を提供しただけなのです
and this gene
そしてこの遺伝子
Then the rest is our bioinformatics method
残りはバイオインフォマティクス手法です
find these information
これらの情報を見つけてください
Then some with Liquid's hands
それからリキッドの手で
Then I found this gene in the second place early in the morning
そして早朝に2番目にこの遺伝子を見つけました
Then use this gene
次に、この遺伝子を使用します
And do liquid association with this gene
そしてこの遺伝子と液体結合を行います
is xy
xyです
find it related
関連するものを見つける
Find a lot more
もっとたくさん見つけてください
According to different data
さまざまなデータによると
This way you get a table
こうすればテーブルが手に入ります
Most importantly, this gene
最も重要なのは、この遺伝子です。
the word of the gene
遺伝子の言葉
Our collaborator is very interested
私たちの協力者は非常に興味を持っています
because they were doing a
彼らはやっていたから
Research
研究
The gene itself is interesting
遺伝子自体が興味深い
Because it is Glutamate
グルタミン酸だから
Glutamate is a
グルタミン酸というのは、
neurotransmitter
神経伝達物質
it's very important
それは非常に重要です
This gene is specialized in this neurotransmitter
この遺伝子はこの神経伝達物質に特化しています
A very important thing that is sent from the inside of the cell to the outside
細胞の中から外へ送られるとても大切なもの
this
これ
protein
タンパク質
OK this
はい、これ
because
なぜなら
sorry this is barely watchable
ごめんなさい、これはほとんど見られません
Because I'm using MaconTosh
MaconToshを使っているので
Every time you turn to this, it turns like this
こちらを向くたびにこうなる
of course it doesn't matter
もちろんそれは関係ありません
These incomprehensible things
こういった不可解なことは
In fact, it was my team who did Gino typing
実際、Gino タイピングを行ったのは私のチームでした
found this
これを見つけました
there is an association
協会があります
But what?
でも何？
The problem is because they use too little data
問題は、使用するデータ量が少なすぎることです
Only about 300
たった300人くらい
So we are publish wanting to publish
だから私たちは出版したいと思って出版しています
So referee told us to do more
だから主審はもっとやれと言った
That
それか
Because of this personnel, resources are limited
この人員のため、リソースは限られています
so we didn't go ahead
だから私たちは先に進まなかった
But what?
でも何？
It happens to be a gift that fell from the sky
それはたまたま空から降ってきた贈り物
just in
ちょうど入ったところ
In 2007
2007年に
在 New England Journal of Medicine
ニューイングランド医学ジャーナルで
There is an article like this
こんな記事があります
this is a very large
これは非常に大きいです
generalized study
総合的な勉強
he used
彼は使った
There are about 12,360 subjects
約12,360科目あります
There are 609 family to you etc.
あなたには609の家族がいます、など。
very large and is
とても大きくて
Cross-centre and transnational cooperation
センターを超えた多国籍協力
They use this generalized association method
彼らはこの一般化された関連付け方法を使用します
Find the two most important experiences
最も重要な 2 つの経験を見つける
One is IL-2R and the other is IL-7
1 つは IL-2R、もう 1 つは IL-7
ah
ああ
Then I see iOS 11
次に、iOS 11が表示されます
This thing seems familiar
このことはよく知られているようです
I'll go back and have a look
戻って見てみます
Hey, if you look at it, this iOS 11A you look at here
ねえ、見てみたら、この iOS 11A ここ見て
So from this totally unrelated genics
したがって、このまったく無関係な遺伝子から
Franchon data
フランションデータ
Through this and this Genex
あれやこれやジェネクスを通して
so go find this
それでこれを探しに行ってください
Then this item is already in referring’s hands
その場合、このアイテムはすでに紹介者の手に渡っています
So we just write a letter saying
だから私たちはこう言う手紙を書くだけです
that this
これは
find is
見つけます
New England Journal of Medicine
ニューイングランド医学ジャーナル
The gene found in the magazine is our gene
雑誌に載った遺伝子は私たちの遺伝子
So this will be unlocked soon
ということで、もうすぐアンロックされる予定です
actually
実際
story behind that is
その裏話は
at this
この時点で
There is a marker near our gene
私たちの遺伝子の近くにマーカーがあります
Use their data with this generalized data
この一般化されたデータを使用してデータを使用する
look this his this
これを見て、彼のこれを
Lot score
ロットスコア
His significance is in fact
彼の重要性は実際には
better than this
これよりも良い
This I-L7R is still high
このI-L7Rはまだ高いです
It means more significant
それはより重要な意味を持ちます
at the same time
同時に
What about the two GINs?
2 つの GIN についてはどうですか?
actually very close
実はとても近い
This is the I-L7R
こちらはI-L7Rです
With this SL C1S
このSL C1Sでは
actually very close
実はとても近い
So what about this paper?
では、この紙はどうでしょうか？
it's easy to accept
受け入れるのは簡単です
But here
しかし、ここで
One thing this Person is complaining about
この人が不満を言っていることが 1 つあります
Actually this I-L7R
実はこのI-L7R
I'll go back and check
戻って確認します
Because the sound is very deep
音がとても深いので
Just check my E-mail
メールをチェックしてください
I sent my Corelibrator in an e-mail
Corelibrator を電子メールで送信しました
In fact, there is a special mention of this
実はこれに関しては特筆すべき点があり、
I tell everyone yes
みんなにそう言います
Between this GIN and this GIN
この GIN とこの GIN の間
very short gap
非常に短いギャップ
Then this is also very important GIN
それから、これも非常に重要なGINです
can they do something
彼らは何かできるでしょうか
This Validation and the like
この検証など
but they didn't do it
しかし彼らはそれをしませんでした
The reason is because of that E-mail
理由はあのメールのせいです
Bounced back
跳ね返った
they didn't send out at all
彼らはまったく発送しなかった
so this
したがって、この
But he might not be able to do it even if they are the same generation.
でも、同世代でもできないかもしれない。
because the words here
なぜならここにある言葉は
Sometimes it's later
場合によっては後になることもあります
We still have a project that is working on this new era
新しい時代に向けたプロジェクトはまだ続いています
It is solid playful
遊び心たっぷりです
what about here
ここはどうですか
There is more information involved
さらに詳しい情報が含まれています
We do Geneexpression probably
私たちはおそらく Geneexpression を行っています
Get the sneeper array of 30,000 Gene
30,000遺伝子のスニーパーアレイを入手
like this next generation
この次世代のように
Its output this data output is
その出力、このデータ出力は
200 MacBits and more
200 MacBits 以上
This is a very large data
これは非常に大きなデータです
So behind this needs a big ID team to do it
したがって、これを行うには大規模な ID チームが必要です
Then we have some computer
それから私たちはコンピューターを持っています
use some of this
これの一部を使って
Through some clusters and so on
いくつかのクラスターなどを経て
do something like this
このようなことをしてください
Then we also have a very good note
それから、とても良いメモもあります
he may not be here
彼はここにいないかもしれない
but he designs
しかし彼はデザインする
The most important thing is to hope that here can
最も重要なことは、ここでそれができることを願うことです
through some information
ある情報を通じて
Accidents that can happen automatically
自動的に起こり得る事故
Because what we often encounter when dealing with these problems is
なぜなら、これらの問題に対処するときに私たちがよく遭遇するのは、
you do something today
あなたは今日何かをします
do something tomorrow
明日何かをする
If there is no system
システムがなかったら
error prone
エラーを起こしやすい
If this error occurs, it will affect many
このエラーが発生すると、多くの人に影響が及びます
so everything
だからすべて
We're all about wanting to be able to
私たちは皆、できるようになりたいと思っています。
online
オンライン
Can use online code to get it out
オンラインコードを使用して取り出すことができます
If you are right, you will always be right
あなたが正しければ、あなたは常に正しいままです
If you are wrong, of course you will always be wrong
あなたが間違っているなら、もちろんあなたは常に間違っているでしょう
So you have to be very, very careful when you first start
したがって、最初に始めるときは非常に注意する必要があります
After that, it doesn't matter
その後は関係ない
Today is this person's operation, tomorrow is that operation
今日はこの人の手術、明日はあの手術
you won't have
あなたにはありません
This information will be passed on
この情報は引き継がれます
generate some errors
いくつかのエラーが発生する
so information
それで情報
Engineering talents help our lab a lot
エンジニアリングの才能が私たちの研究室を大いに助けてくれます
Then I want to end with this thing
それではこの件で終わりにしたいと思います
in 2004
2004年に
this
これ
Professor Joe Cohen
ジョー・コーエン教授
he is
彼は
one of rockfellow
rockfellow的一個
very famous population
非常に有名な人々
Professor of Genetics
遺伝学の教授
He wrote articles like this
彼はこのような記事を書きました
The picture itself is very obvious
写真自体は非常にわかりやすいです
Mathematics is
数学は
biologist's next microscope only better
生物学者の次の顕微鏡はさらに優れています
biologist's mathematics next physics only better
生物学者の数学の次は物理学だけが優れている
that means yes
それははいという意味です
in biology
生物学で
Is it a problem in many trees?
多くの木に問題があるのでしょうか？
are developing
発展している
After that, there will be more and more business
その後もビジネスはどんどん増えていきます
So this is a pretty important direction
これは非常に重要な方向性です
That
それか
Almost over
もうすぐ終わり
Then this liquid association
そして、この液体結合は
Here is a profile from this creature
この生き物のプロフィールはこちら
Concepts developed
開発されたコンセプト
Can it be used in other contacts?
他の連絡先でも使用できますか?
I'm sure there are many places to use
きっと使えるところがたくさんあると思います
Actually, I told my daughter before
実は、前に娘に言いました。
I want to explain what this liquid association is
この液体結合とは何なのか説明したいと思います
Just think about your relationship with your friends
友達との関係を考えてみてください
good relationship sometimes
時には良い関係
That's like repository creation
それはリポジトリの作成のようなものです
but when you're in a bad mood
でも機嫌が悪いときは
The machinery is broken
機械が壊れている
Then your relationship with him may be
そうなると、あなたと彼との関係は、
So your positive negative
つまり、あなたのポジティブネガティブ
Does it change with your mood or how?
気分や気分によって変わりますか？
Sometimes it will be positive and sometimes it will be negative
ポジティブな場合もあれば、ネガティブな場合もあります
look at it from another angle
別の角度から見てください
look at another question
別の質問を見てください
It should be a few days from now
今から数日後のはずです
Many people may have to take the exam
多くの人が試験を受けなければならないかもしれない
Then you see from the exam
それなら試験を見ればわかります
Your preparation time and your grade
準備時間と成績
Is it effective?
効果はあるのでしょうか？
You may talk to your children, friends
お子様やお友達とお話してもいいですね
noisy for a long time
長時間騒々しい
Sometimes it works
時々それはうまくいきます
Sometimes it doesn't work
うまくいかないこともあります
The more you prepare, of course the grades will come.
準備をすればするほど、当然成績も上がります。
I have been preparing for half a day
半日かけて準備してきました
But these many different backgrounds
しかし、これらのさまざまな背景
For example, a state of health
たとえば、健康状態
If you say you are in good spirits
元気だと言ったら
you are of course very effective
あなたはもちろんとても有能です
The more you prepare, the better your grades
準備すればするほど成績は上がる
then your health is not good
それならあなたの健康状態は良くありません
you have been sick
あなたは病気になっています
Then you'll be wasting your time if you're ready.
準備ができていれば時間を無駄にすることになります。
Then maybe there is no correlation
それなら相関関係はないかもしれない
or have cross-correlation
または相互相関がある
So this idea that liquid has learned
つまり、液体が学んだこの考えは、
is actually quite common
実際には非常に一般的です
almost in personal life
ほぼ私生活の中で
He can use various
彼はいろいろ使えます
This data, its calculation method is also very simple
このデータ、計算方法も非常に簡単です
In that regard, I think this
その点で、私はこう思います
Basically the relationship between these two variables
基本的にこれら 2 つの変数間の関係
In fact, is it forever?
実際、それは永遠なのでしょうか？
then i want to carry the message here
それではここにメッセージを伝えたいと思います
OK everybody
はい、皆さん
That's some relevant information
それはいくつかの関連情報です
If you are interested, go and see
興味があれば行って見てください
Then I want to thank some past colleagues
それから、過去の同僚に感謝したいと思います
And then there are colleagues who are currently working on this
そして、現在これに取り組んでいる同僚がいます
And this Haida team
そしてこのハイダチーム
There is also this Director of Combat Skills who can turn around in the sea
海中で向きを変えるこの戦闘スキルのディレクターもいます
And provide us with a lot of information
そしてたくさんの情報を提供してください
ok thank you everyone
わかりました、みんなありがとう
Thanks
ありがとう
What's your problem?
あなたの問題は何ですか？
I would like to ask a question, now we are making the entire genetic line of the wedding paper in Taiwan
質問したいのですが、現在台湾では結婚式の書類の遺伝子系統全体を作成しています。
Came to find this Target Drog Dachanghai seems to have a special achievement
このターゲット・ドッグを見つけに来たDachanghaiは特別な功績を持っているようです
But the cost is very high, and health insurance costs more than 20,000 yuan
しかし費用は非常に高く、健康保険料は2万元以上かかります。
I think this will have a relatively stable price in the future around your research journal
あなたの研究雑誌の周りで、これは将来的に比較的安定した価格になると思います
or expand to other cancers
または他のがんに拡大する
I think you may be asking the wrong person.
もしかしたら質問する相手を間違えているのではないかと思います。
Because we do statistics, I can't help
私たちは統計をやっているので、私は助けることができません
I guess our job is to help people who develop
私たちの仕事は、発展する人々を助けることだと思います
Then maybe be able to find a more effective marker
そうすれば、より効果的なマーカーを見つけることができるかもしれません
If you only need the proper information
適切な情報だけが必要な場合
If those markers say that elder brother lost
もしその標識が兄が負けたと言うなら
not much and very effective
それほど多くはなく、非常に効果的です
In fact, its price should be much lower than that of
実際、その価格は他のものよりもはるかに低いはずです。
so this is
それでこれは
Eventure will also have
イベントにもあります
The ultimate goal, of course
最終目標はもちろん
The whole method should be quite civilian
手法全体は非常に民間的なものでなければなりません
So these things like genetic testing are still
つまり、遺伝子検査のようなことはまだ行われています
the future is if it really works really
それが本当にうまくいくかどうかが未来だ
It's really easy to promote
プロモーションするのは本当に簡単です
Must be pretty cheap when mass produced
量産すればかなり安くなるはず
like i just mentioned
先ほど述べたように
EGFR Mutation on lung cancer
肺がんに対するEGFR変異
Now I listen to that Professor Yang
今私はヤン教授の話を聞きます
You have been judged as lung adenocarcinoma
肺腺がんと判定されました
Especially if you are a gland, you will definitely make one like this
特に腺系なら絶対こういうの作るよ
Pest
害虫
EGFR TEST
EGFR検査
Because there are already medicines over there that can target this aspect
なぜなら、この側面をターゲットにすることができる薬がすでにそこにあるからです
Then our current work is mainly aimed at
そして、私たちの現在の仕事は主に次のことを目的としています
Of course that medicine is effective, but not everyone is effective
もちろんその薬は効果がありますが、すべての人に効果があるわけではありません
still some people are bad
まだ悪い人もいる
Now it's just the gas meter
今はガスメーターだけです
He wants more than 20,000 yuan
彼は2万元以上欲しい
Just look for that gene's calmness
その遺伝子の静けさを探してください
Calm down, I don't know about the holidays
落ち着いてください、休日のことは知りません
Thank you
ありがとう
Hello, Professor, I would like to ask
こんにちは、教授、お尋ねしたいのですが
Questions about experiments
実験に関する質問
Professor, I just said that liquid sometimes learns to choose
教授、先ほど言いました、液体は時々選択を学ぶと
The professor mentioned that he needs many conditions
教授は多くの条件が必要だと言いました
That Error to find out the Target
ターゲットを見つけるためのエラー
Well, I have two questions
さて、質問が2つあります
One is to say how many conditions are needed to do this
1 つは、これを行うにはいくつの条件が必要かということです。
Then there is the second question
それから2番目の質問です
like this is to do it yourself
これは自分で行うことです
Or is there some online
それともオンラインにもあるのでしょうか
It may be that someone else shares it for analysis.
他の誰かが分析のためにそれを共有している可能性があります。
i think that
私はそう思います
in two programs
2つのプログラムで
One is to tell you how to do it
一つはやり方を教えること
When can some interesting results be found
興味深い結果が見つかるのはいつですか
Or the results that are believed in by statistics
あるいは統計によって信じられている結果
How much condition does this need
これはどのくらいの条件が必要ですか
This depends on your liquid itself first
これはまず液体自体に依存します
About the size of your earring
イヤリングのサイズについて
If it is a student of Liquid, his strength is very high
リキッドの生徒ならその力は非常に高い
Then the conditions you need will not be very big
そうすれば、必要な条件はそれほど大きくなくなります
Then we did an analysis before
その後、事前に分析を行いました
About the same number of conditions
ほぼ同じ数の条件
Probably around 50 or so
たぶん50くらいかな
If the fifth is
5番目なら
Roughly the results obtained are statistically
得られた結果はおおよそ統計的に
Probably none that reaches a certain level of salience
おそらく、特定のレベルの顕著性に達するものはありません
this is this one
これはこれです
According to our semiation study
私たちのセミエーション研究によると
Is it possible to use the data of this public domain
このパブリックドメインのデータを利用することは可能ですか？
my answer is yes
私の答えは「はい」です
Because the first one is useless
前者は駄目だから
With the lady over there, you can get it out and you can
あそこの女性がいれば、それを取り出すことができます、そして、
some relationships can be found
いくつかの関係が見つかります
and then further confirm
そしてさらに確認します
that in fact we are
実際に私たちはそうだということ
like the examples I just gave
先ほど挙げた例のように
is an example of Multiple Squares
複数の正方形の例です
That's exactly Public Domain stuff
それはまさにパブリックドメインのものです
at the same time
同時に
Now maybe your own personal laboratory
もしかしたらあなた自身の個人的な研究室かもしれません
Take some data yourself
自分でデータを取得する
that amount may not be much
その量は多くないかもしれない
Then you can find some examples of genes
次に、遺伝子の例をいくつか見つけることができます。
Moderators can go further with these little experiments
モデレータはこれらの小さな実験をさらに進めることができます
I found several genes
いくつかの遺伝子を見つけた
Then you have to go further
それならさらに先に進まなければなりません
Go and see the genes related to the influence of these genes
これらの遺伝子の影響に関連する遺伝子を見に行ってください。
You can go to the Internet to look up more information about this performance
インターネットにアクセスして、このパフォーマンスに関する詳細情報を検索できます。
Then through this method
それからこの方法を通して
come with SIMELE
SIMELEが付属しています
Students who use Corealization or Request
Corealization または Request を使用する学生
In fact, our lab uses both
実際、私たちの研究室では両方を使用しています
Then you can get some more information
その後、さらに詳しい情報を得ることができます
then bring it back
それからそれを元に戻します
Then you can take your experiment a step further
そうすれば、実験をさらに一歩進めることができます
So these are auxiliary
したがって、これらは補助的なものです
or tools
またはツール
Hello teacher, thank you for your lecture
こんにちは、先生、講義ありがとうございました
i want to ask
聞きたいです
When using liquid association
液体会合剤を使用する場合
There are a lot of situations coming out
色々な状況が出てきます
but i think
しかし、私は思います
According to what you just said
あなたが今言ったことによると
It seems that there are at least three situations
少なくとも3つの状況があるようです
Positively correlated positively correlated with each other
正の相関がある 互いに正の相関がある
Of course if this
もちろんこれなら
positive correlation and positive correlation
正の相関と正の相関
There are also positive correlations with each other
互いに正の相関関係もあります
or the one of omniscience and interrelationship
あるいは全知と相互関係のもの
If the demarcation point is not adjusted properly
境界点が正しく調整されていない場合
In fact, the data is still messy
実際、データはまだ乱雑です
That
それか
At the beginning of the research
研究の初めに
For example, how did the professor find out
たとえば、教授はどうやってそれを見つけたのか
How to cut those states
それらの状態をどのように切断するか
OK
OK
the cutting words
鋭い言葉
because our theory is
なぜなら私たちの理論は
no need to cut
切る必要はありません
we're thinking of it as this
私たちはそれをこのように考えています
state is a continuous state
状態は継続的な状態です
Then through some calculus methods
次に、いくつかの微積分法を介して
go get it out
取りに行って出しなさい
so
それで
It's not that it's OK, I'll cut to this side, to this side
大丈夫ってわけじゃないよ、こっちへ、こっちへ、切ってやるよ
then compare
それから比較してください
That is
あれは
I originally thought the same way
私ももともと同じように思っていました
But want to say like you just said
でも、あなたが今言ったように言いたいのです
Then I have to cut 50%
それなら50％カットしなきゃいけない
or 30%
または30%
how is it possible
どのようにして可能ですか
Every gene is different
遺伝子は一つ一つ違う
Well, that's actually what we saw in the end.
まあ、それが実際に私たちが最終的に見たものです。
so that's why this
だからこれは
Well
良い
do some math with words
単語を使って計算する
There are always some people whose problem is
常に問題を抱えている人がいます。
oops
おっと
Although uh intuitive
まあ直感的ですが
It is easier to think about it with this discrete method
この離散法で考えると楽です
But doing the math above is to think of it as a continuous
しかし、上記の計算を行うことは、それを連続的なものと考えることです。
will be easier
より簡単になります
So here, the whole sear
それで、ここで、全体を焼きます
this definition of mathematics
この数学の定義
is to use an assumption to say that this change
この変化は次のような仮定を使用します。
In fact, the change of state is a continuous change
実際、状態の変化は継続的な変化です
Then it has normal discretion
それなら通常の裁量権がある
Then through a lema called a stine
それからスタインと呼ばれるレマを通して
that's professor of stine fire
それはスタイン・ファイアー教授です
then he does some
それから彼はいくつかのことをします
uh director
ああ、監督
And then at the end of the day to quit that simple company
そして一日の終わりには、その単純な会社を辞めることになる
and then to the last words
そして最後の言葉まで
Then find out how to cut this gene
次に、この遺伝子を切断する方法を調べます
that's easier
そのほうが簡単です
You can try it with
試してみることができます
We are on our computing workstation
私たちはコンピューティングワークステーション上にいます
On the Internet, we do two ways
インターネットでは 2 つの方法があります
One is to use the Maxmolecular method
1 つは Maxmolecular メソッドを使用することです
The other is to use Discrete
もう 1 つはディスクリートを使用することです
directly to calculate
直接計算するには
Director Li's speech is wonderful
リー監督のスピーチは素晴らしい
i meet you after the afternoon
午後以降に会います
Won't go there again...
あれにはもう行かない...
run away
逃げる
i have two questions
質問が2つあります
The first one is about the lung cancer thing you just talked about
一つ目は、先ほどお話しした肺がんについてです。
Later you also mentioned that non-smoking women have a high incidence of incidents in Taiwan
その後、台湾では非喫煙者の女性の事件発生率が高いともおっしゃっていましたね。
Are these five signature genes related to that?
これら5つの特徴的な遺伝子はそれに関係しているのでしょうか？
That is to say, did you subset when analyzing?
つまり、分析するときにサブセット化しましたか?
See which respects are in the end
最終的にどの敬意が表れるのかを確認する
with that...
それと...
that...
それか...
The paper of the five genes, I think they didn't do the classification like that at that time
5つの遺伝子の論文、当時はそんな分類はしてなかったと思う
At that time, according to the title, he just flew the small one
あの時はタイトルの通り、小さいのを飛ばしただけだった
that lung cancer
その肺がん
For this classification, it is divided into this adinocasinoma
この分類では、このアディノカジノ腫に分けられます。
is our latest job
それは私たちの最近の仕事です
And then our latest work is now this adinocasinoma
そして私たちの最新作がこのアディノカジノマです
At the same time, it is based on whether he has EGF ammutation
同時に、EGF切断があるかどうかに基づいています
Let's do a comparison and then look at the formula on his molecule
比較してから彼の分子の式を見てみましょう
So what are you still doing because it's important
大事なことだからまだ何してるの？
I heard that only the ones in Taiwan have this kind
こういうのは台湾にしかないそうですよ
In comparison, there are actually a lot of Asians
それに比べてアジア人は本当に多い
For Japan, there are a lot of things to wait for
日本にとって、待っていることはたくさんある
But there is a fundamental
しかし、基本的なものがあります
That is, Teacher Ya and the others are most interested in it.
つまり、Ya先生たちが最も興味を持っているのです。
That is, although everyone has discussed a lot about the connection method
つまり、接続方法については皆さんよく議論されていますが、
Anyway, I think this Adino Castiglino
とにかく、私はこのアディーノ・カスティグリーノだと思います
It was Adino Castiglino who was only recently recognized as
アディーノ・カスティグリーノはつい最近になって知られるようになった。
of a new form
一種新的形態的
In the past, it was probably mixed with Squamers
昔はおそらくスクォマーと混ざっていたのだろう
recent words
最近の言葉
So according to the world this is just an international organization
つまり、世界によれば、これは単なる国際機関です
Have had it tested on the ring saying it's a
リング上でテストしてもらったところ、
So in this piece
そこでこの作品では
At present, what I want to know most is
今、一番知りたいのは、
According to Mutation and without Mutation
突然変異による場合と突然変異なしの場合
what is the difference
違いはなんですか
It's not just a single Mutation that makes the difference
違いを生むのは単一の突然変異だけではありません
There are already many other classics in the surrounding area that have followed suit
周辺エリアには、これに倣った他の多くの古典的な施設がすでにあります。
That's what I'm currently working on
それが私が今取り組んでいることです
So we base this
したがって、これをベースにします
Copy number of variation and gene expression等等
変異のコピー数と遺伝子発現等
I believe many people are waiting to see
楽しみに待っている人も多いと思います
this very important program
この非常に重要なプログラム
The most important thing is to need a large sample
最も重要なことは、大量のサンプルが必要であることです
the most important
最も重要な
I have another question is
もう一つ質問があるのですが、
about for example
たとえばについて
When it should have been broken
壊れるべきだったとき
It is Messy data
めちゃくちゃなデータです
In fact, for biologists
実際、生物学者にとっては
A lot of it is that the system itself is very messy
多くの場合、システム自体が非常に厄介であることが原因です
So it's not easy to do experiments
だから実験するのは簡単ではない
part i believe many
私は多くの人を信じています
biological data
生物学的データ
Without doing statistics
統計をとらずに
because make it last and equal to one
なぜならそれを持続させて1に等しいからです
There are many times when we do experiments
実験をすることが多いです
Because a lot of money
お金がたくさんあるから
or resources limit
またはリソース制限
hardly anyone says
ほとんど誰も言いません
do an experiment to repeat
繰り返す実験をする
Experiment twenty times can
20回実験すればできる
到statistically significant
統計的に有意
so i don't know
だから分からない
developments in this area
この分野の発展
Said whether it has reached a certain level
一定のレベルに達しているかどうかを述べた
So can biologist
生物学者もそうだよ
some suggest
いくつかは提案します
How to use the least method
最小限の方法を使用する方法
results that can be obtained
得られる結果
able to be treated like this
このように扱うことができます
Statistically significant data like this
このような統計的に重要なデータ
because you know now
あなたは今知っているから
final result
最後結果
A while ago they found out that
少し前に彼らはそれを知りました
Almost even if it's a different company
たとえ違う会社であっても
with the same data
同じデータで
The results of these cups are about 40 to 50 completely different
これらのカップの結果は約 40 ～ 50 完全に異なります。
So, for example, by using your method to see
したがって、たとえば、あなたのメソッドを使用して、
Could you please help us solve these problems?
これらの問題の解決を手伝ってもらえませんか?
How to design an experiment
実験をデザインする方法
I think your topic is very good
あなたのトピックはとても良いと思います
Because you said N equal to 1
N が 1 に等しいと言ったからです
In fact, many times although you have a lot of N
実際、N がたくさんあるにもかかわらず、何度も
But the last words are only in the case of a N equal to 1
ただし、最後の単語は N が 1 の場合のみです。
Because another experiment was placed
別の実験が置かれたため
Although they took 100 pictures
写真を100枚撮ったのに
But his N and N are under completely different circumstances
しかし、彼のNとNは全く異なる状況にあります
Then this one is to think about it from the perspective of the network
次に、ネットワークの観点から考えてみます。
That is to say, if today
つまり、今日だったら
Many units are willing to send money down
多くのユニットが送金に応じてくれます
Then do some more systematic design
次に、より体系的な設計を行います
Then don't say you just thought of something
じゃあ、ちょっと思いついたとか言わないでね
just think of what to do
何をすべきかを考えてください
Between many N equal to 1
1 に等しい多数の N の間
can also have some hosts
いくつかのホストを持つこともできます
will be better
良くなります
If so
もしそうなら
you can combine different labs
さまざまなラボを組み合わせることができます
A big M comes out like a string
大きなMが紐のように出てきます
that's there
それはそこにあります
Now it is through the Internet
今はインターネット経由です
a lot of this information
この情報の多くを
you can take it
あなたはそれを取ることができます
charge up
充電する
Do some Metal Analyze
金属分析をしてみよう
I don't really like Metal Analyze
メタルアナライズはあまり好きではない
this idea
このアイデア
Because many times it is Trivial
多くの場合それは些細なことだから
ready to use
使用する準備ができて
that means ok i do this
つまり、わかりました、これをやります
what to see
何を見てください
Significantly
大幅
I will make it a PV
PVにさせていただきます
those things have
それらのものは持っています
Significantly
大幅
Just post it as a PV
PVとして投稿するだけ
In the end you use a
最終的には、
Same level company
同レベルの会社
A PV that was born
生まれたPV
Actually Metal Analyze
実際に金属を分析してみる
its
これは
significance
意義
more than this
これ以上
it should go to enalyze
分析しに行くべきだ
After all
結局
which laboratories
どの研究室
Why with which labs
なぜどの研究室で行うのか
Which laboratories will be the same
どの研究室が同じになるか
with which labs
どの研究室と
why is it different
なぜ違うのですか
That
それか
where is the same reason
同じ理由がどこにあるのか
or same reason where
または同じ理由で
The reasons for these are the number of positions
その理由はポジションの多さです
right
右
But the number of positions
でもポジションの数は
if you have eyes
目があるなら
it will be
そうなる
then no one knows
それなら誰も知らない
So we can make an assumption
したがって、仮定を立てることができます
Perhaps these positions are
おそらくこれらのポジションは、
Maybe it can be expressed through some variables
もしかしたら変数で表現できるかもしれない
those variables maybe
それらの変数はおそらく
In fact, it may be the condition of the West
実際、それが西洋の状況なのかもしれない
how like
どうですか
Then these things can
そうすれば、これらのことができます
expressed by certain genes
特定の遺伝子によって発現される
So in fact there is a way
それで実際には方法があります
When there were many genes
遺伝子がたくさんあった頃
Liquid Association
液体結合
in fact a
実際には
I think
私が思うに
The formula of Liquid Association is not necessarily necessary
液体会合の公式は必ずしも必要ではない
but the basic idea of ​​it
しかし、その基本的な考え方は
It should be able to be used to manage
管理に使用できるはずです
Because the most important thing is to find some potential factors
最も重要なことは、いくつかの潜在的な要因を見つけることであるため、
If the factors that existed before
以前に存在した要因がある場合、
Original words look
オリジナルの言葉の見た目
two time to make it
2回で完成します
The result is not related at all.
結果は全く関係ありません。
that may be under certain conditions
それは特定の条件下で発生する可能性があります
they will have related
彼らは関連するでしょう
ask your boss
上司に聞いてください
just now you mentioned that
たった今それを言いましたね
Is it correct to match the big A with the small questions?
大きなAと小さな質問を一致させるのは正しいですか？
That G type
あのGタイプ
Then A and G are not compatible
するとAとGは互換性がありません
That
それか
If say cross match
クロスマッチと言えば
G matches T, A matches, okay?
G は T に一致し、A は一致します。
G matching type, A matching type
Gマッチングタイプ、Aマッチングタイプ
Like this, is it possible?
このように、可能でしょうか？
The No. 8 calculus seems to be forming wind
8番の微分積分が風を起こしているようだ
So fixed A must match T
したがって、A は T と一致する必要があると修正されました
Can't change the cross
クロスは変えられない
No way, it has some chemical properties
まさか、化学的性質があるとは
It's swords between each other, how about its attraction
剣と剣、その魅力はどうですか？
and its structure
とその構造
In fact, this is an important concept
実は、これは重要な概念なのです
In this way, it will be...
このようにして、それは...
It is this DNA that will make a pair and not mess up
この DNA がペアを作り、混乱させないのです
If it is not like that, then the structure is very unstable
そうでない場合、その構造は非常に不安定です
Hello Professor
こんにちは教授
We are now working on the Biohometase part
現在、Biohometase の部分に取り組んでいます
Generally speaking, there are two ways
大まかに言うと2つの方法があります
One is the statistical way you just talked about
1 つは、先ほど話した統計的な方法です。
It’s just that everyone compares it, and what many people are using is data mining.
誰もがそれを比較しており、多くの人がデータマイニングを使用しているだけです
In your opinion, what is the biggest difference between these two people?
この二人の最大の違いは何だと思いますか?
Or how do people feel that these two
あるいは、人々はこの 2 つをどのように感じますか
Is there some kind of special opinion?
何か特別な意見があるのでしょうか？
ok that's a good question
わかりました、それは良い質問です
That data mining is actually an informatics scientist
データマイニングの担当者は実は情報科学者だ
I don't know if it was stolen
盗まれたかどうかはわかりません
Imagine a rather new way to develop statistics
統計を作成するためのかなり新しい方法を想像してください
because statisticians
なぜなら統計学者は
This statistic itself sounds like crying and tasteless
この統計自体が泣き叫ぶようで味気ない
data analysis sound analysis data
データ解析 音解析データ
to call out a
を呼び出す
How about BetaMade in Chinese?
中国語の BetaMade はどうですか?
data mining
データマイニング
Mining doesn't sound good.
採掘は良くないようです。
But carbon health is not good
しかし炭素の健康は良くない
But English itself is very nice
でも英語自体はとてもいいです
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
is data mining itself
データマイニングそのものです
I'm human so what do you think
私も人間だからどう思う？
data mining you turn it into data
データマイニング、それをデータに変える
Do you want to poke around like the unminer?
採掘者のように探索してみませんか?
Does that sound like a lot?
それはたくさんあるように思えますか？
It's not that hard, is it?
そんなに難しくないですよね？
But DataMind is going to dig some information
しかし、DataMind はいくつかの情報を掘り出す予定です
A lot of statistical concepts are used there
そこでは多くの統計概念が使用されています
There are many things of course a computer scientist
コンピューター科学者にはもちろんたくさんのことがあります
himself according to his intuition
自分自身の直感に従って
can match many things
多くのものに合わせることができます
these things
これらの事
Let's not talk about which school this is.
これがどの学校であるかについては話さないようにしましょう。
For example, DataMind uses a lot of support vector machines
たとえば、DataMind は多くのサポート ベクター マシンを使用します。
If it supports vector machine, it is used for classification
ベクトルマシンをサポートしている場合は、分類に使用されます
Vasus has a set of discreement like RFVsure
Vasus には RFVsure のような一連の裁量権があります
Who is better then?
それでは誰が優れているでしょうか？
So that actually depends on the structure of the different states
つまり、それは実際にはさまざまな州の構造に依存します
When there is a lot of noise in the Vsure of RFVsure
RFVsureのVsureにノイズが多い場合
it will be more effective
より効果的になります
SupportVeq's Machine is in the data
SupportVeq のマシンはデータ内にあります
its this
それはこれです
Less noise
ノイズが少ない
But the state is complicated
しかし状態は複雑です
When the Covered Manifold is more complicated
被覆多様体がより複雑な場合
it will be more effective
より効果的になります
So each has many different degrees
したがって、それぞれにさまざまな程度があります
That
それか
concepts used
使用される概念
you could say statistics
統計と言ってもいいでしょう
aka mathematics
別名数学
anyway
ともかく
It's all logic
それはすべて論理です
A methodical approach to data analysis
データ分析への系統的なアプローチ
so it can be useful in certain situations
したがって、特定の状況では役立つ可能性があります
OK
OK
besides
そのほか
close first
先關一下
we today
今日の私たち
this page you know so far
あなたがこれまでに知っているこのページ
thanks again
再度、感謝します
Thank you Zhou Da
周達さん、ありがとう